<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-110.03</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on May 14, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§50-110.03(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Operation of a personal delivery device.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A permit holder may operate a PDD that complies with <cite path="50|1A">this chapter</cite> on sidewalks and crosswalks in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To operate in the District, a PDD shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Obey all traffic control devices and signs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Operate in a safe and non-hazardous manner that does not endanger traffic or property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not unreasonably interfere with traffic;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not transport any hazardous materials or waste;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Clearly and conspicuously display the contact information of the permit holder operating the PDD; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Not exceed 250 pounds in weight, excluding any property being carried by the PDD, or a higher weight limit established by the Department through rulemaking.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A PDD shall have the same obligations and rights-of-way as a pedestrian under similar circumstances, except that a PDD shall yield the right-of-way to traffic.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, a PDD shall not constitute a vehicle or motor vehicle for any purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a technology failure or loss of communication occurs during the operation of a PDD, the PDD shall alert the operator and, if the PDD operator is unable to assume direct control of the device, come to an off-roadway stop.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a PDD comes to an off-roadway stop under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the owner of the PDD shall promptly remove the PDD.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-137" eff="2018-07-17" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-137" eff="2018-07-17" path="§4" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-125" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-08-12" eff="2025-08-12">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-125" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Personal Delivery Device Weight Limit Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-125, Aug. 12, 2025, 72 DCR 8603)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-08-12" doc="D.C. Act 26-125" eff="2025-08-12" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-48" eff="2025-10-01" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-48" eff="2025-10-01" path="§2|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-48" eff="2025-10-01" path="§2|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-48" eff="2025-10-01" path="§2|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 26-48" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-10-01" eff="2025-10-01">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-48" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Personal Delivery Device Weight Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Law 26-48, Oct. 1, 2025, 72 DCR 8945)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
