<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2462</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Unlawful acts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be a violation of <cite path="50|23">Chapter 23 of this title</cite>, for any person to park or store:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An abandoned or dangerous vehicle on public space;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any motor vehicle on private property without the consent of the property owner; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An abandoned or dangerous vehicle on private property, even with the consent of the property owner, unless the vehicle is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Kept in a lawful enclosed structure or building completely shielded from the view of individuals on the adjoining properties; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Lawfully stored or kept on the property of a business engaged in the lawful repair, storage, salvage, or disposal of vehicles.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be a defense to a violation under subsection (a) of this section if the vehicle owner filed a report, including the time and date of the event, with the Metropolitan Police Department or the vehicle owner's insurer about the damage to the vehicle, prior to receiving the notice of infraction; provided, that such defense shall be valid for no more than 15 business days after the owner filed the damage report and may not be raised again after the expiration of the 15-day period for the same event or incident.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="I|D" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="ยง132" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
