<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2431</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="50|24A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Abandoned vehicle" means any motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer that is left, parked, or stored on public space for more than 48 hours or on private property for more than 30 days, and to which at least one of the following applies:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is apparently inoperable, including a vehicle missing its transmission, motor, or one or more tires, and is not undergoing emergency repair;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The vehicle serves as harborage for rats, vermin, and other pests; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The vehicle does not display valid vehicle identification tags, a valid registration sticker, or is an unidentifiable vehicle; except, that a vehicle shall not be deemed an abandoned vehicle under this subparagraph solely because the vehicle displays expired tags or registration sticker, unless the tags or registration sticker expired at least one year before any enforcement action is taken under <cite path="50|24A">this chapter</cite>, which shall be measured concurrently with the period of time required to establish that the vehicle is abandoned, as described in the lead-in language of this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Dangerous vehicle" means a motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer that, due to at least one of the following conditions existing for at least 24 hours, poses an imminent hazard to the public health, safety, or welfare:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is extensively damaged, including damaged by fire or exposed broken glass or metal shards are present; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Another dangerous condition that poses an imminent hazard to the public health, safety, or welfare is present.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Department" means the Department of Public Works.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of Public Works.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Immobilization device" means a device or mechanism that, when equipped to a motor vehicle, prevents the motor vehicle's operation but causes no damage to the motor vehicle unless the motor vehicle is moved while such device or mechanism is in place.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Immobilization-eligible vehicle" means a vehicle that meets the requirements of <cite path="§50-2452">§ 50-2452</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Impounded" means a vehicle in the custody of the Department of Public Works or stored at a private storage facility at the direction of the Department as a result of the vehicle:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Having been removed from its location pursuant to District laws or regulations; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Having been transferred from the custody of the Metropolitan Police Department, or other agency, to the custody of the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>"LPRS" means license plate recognition system, which is an electronic device that may be handheld, mounted on a vehicle, or positioned in a stationary location and is capable of recording data on, or taking a photograph of, a vehicle or its vehicle identification tag and comparing the collected data and photographs to existing databases for investigative and enforcement purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Motor vehicle" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-2301.02|(5A)">§ 50-2301.02(5A)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>"Park" means to leave any motor vehicle standing on a public right-of-way, public space, or private space, either attended or unattended.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>"Parking violation" means a violation of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text><cite path="§50-1501.04a">§ 50-1501.04a</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text><cite path="§50-2637">§ 50-2637</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>§§ <cite path="§50-2454">50-2454</cite> and <cite path="§50-2462">50-2462</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Other parking, standing, and non-moving violations committed with a motor vehicle and adjudicated pursuant to <cite path="§50-2303.01">§ 50-2303.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>"Physical characteristics of an abandoned vehicle" means any of the conditions set forth in paragraph (1) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>"Private property" means real property, including real property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District , other than public space.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>"Public right-of-way" means the surface, air space above the surface, and area below the surface of any public street, highway, bridge, tunnel, alley, or sidewalk.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>"Public space" means all the property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District, between lines on a street, as such property lines are shown on the records of the Surveyor of the District, and includes any public right-of-way, tree space, sidewalk, or parking between such property lines.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>"Safety-sensitive parking violation" means a stopping, standing, or parking violation that poses an immediate risk to the safety of users of public rights-of-way, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Obstruction of a crosswalk, sidewalk, alley, driveway, or intersection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Stopping, standing, or parking in a fire lane, within 10 feet of a fire hydrant, or other violations that impact fire safety and emergency response;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Unauthorized stopping, standing, or parking in spaces reserved for individuals with disabilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Stopping, standing, or parking in a bus lane, bus parking zone, bicycle lane, or other shared use path; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Other violations as determined by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>"Unidentifiable vehicle" means any vehicle found parked on any public right-of-way or public space in the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>That does not have a vehicle identification tag displayed or affixed to the vehicle;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>With an obscured or illegible vehicle identification number;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Displaying a counterfeit, stolen, or otherwise fraudulent vehicle identification tag in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Displaying a vehicle identification tag not identifiable in the directory required by <cite path="§50-2444">§ 50-2444</cite>, or with a vehicle identification tag that can otherwise be clearly identified as counterfeit, altered, or otherwise fraudulent by visual inspection alone;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Using any tinted, colored, painted, marked, clear, or illuminated object that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Covers any of the characters of a vehicle's vehicle identification tag; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Distorts an image recorded by automated traffic enforcement or license plate recognition system of any of the characters of a vehicle's vehicle identification tag or other identifying features.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Is obscured by a vehicle cover or tarp that obscures the vehicle identification tags; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Has other characteristics that otherwise restrict the ability to issue the vehicle a notice of infraction for parking enforcement or automated traffic enforcement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>"Vehicle" means motor vehicle.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>"Vehicle identification number" means a unique alphanumeric code or serial number used by the automotive industry to identify an individual motor vehicle when a vehicle is manufactured.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>"Vehicle identification tag" means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A permanent plate or tag issued by a jurisdiction containing letters, numerals, or a combination of both, attached to a motor vehicle, that serves as a unique identifier matching that motor vehicle; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A temporary vehicle tag, dealer's tag, or manufacturer's tag issued in any jurisdiction for a vehicle awaiting issuance of permanent license plates.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="I|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="§102" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
