<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2455</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Immobilized and impounded vehicles; notice to owners and lienholders.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In any case involving immobilization of a vehicle pursuant to <cite path="50|24A">this chapter</cite>, such law enforcement officer or employee shall cause to be placed on such vehicle, in a conspicuous manner, notice sufficient to warn any individual to the effect that such vehicle has been immobilized and that any attempt to move such vehicle might result in damage to such vehicle.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before the removal of an immobilization device from a motor vehicle or the release of a motor vehicle from impoundment, the owner shall pay all outstanding fees, charges, civil fines, or penalties against the owner or any motor vehicle in which the owner has an ownership interest or had an ownership interest when a notice of infraction was issued</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the vehicle was immobilized or impounded with 10 or more vehicle infraction points assessed for violations pursuant to <cite path="§50-2451">§50-2451(b)</cite>, or other moving violations as determined by the Mayor, the owner shall also provide evidence of completion of a safe-driving course created pursuant to <cite path="§50-1405.02">§50-1405.02(a)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except for vehicles disposed of pursuant to <cite path="§50-2465">§ 50-2465</cite>, the Department shall send an impoundment notice, by first class mail, to the last known address of the owners of record of an impounded vehicle, and any lienholders of record, as that information is indicated in the records of the Department of Motor Vehicles or in the records of the appropriate agency of the jurisdiction where the vehicle is registered. If the vehicle was seized from private property other than real property owned or under the jurisdiction of the District, notice shall also be sent, by first class mail, to the owner of that property, as indicated in the records of the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The impoundment notice required by subsection (c) of this section shall be mailed no later than 5 days after the vehicle is received at an impoundment or storage facility and shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Describe the year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of each vehicle;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Indicate the reason why the vehicle was impounded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If impounded for violating <cite path="§50-2462">§ 50-2462</cite>, indicate the nature of the violation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Advise the owner and lienholders of the procedures for reclaiming the vehicle and the applicable reclamation period for doing so; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Warn the owner and lienholders that the vehicle will be sold, or otherwise disposed of, if those procedures are not completed by the expiration of the reclamation period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the address of the owner or lienholders cannot be determined, the Department shall publish an impoundment notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the District within 10 days after a vehicle is received at an impoundment or storage facility. If the mailed notice is returned as undeliverable within 14 days after mailing, an impoundment notice shall also be published. The published notice may contain a listing of more than one vehicle and shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Describe the year, make, model, and vehicle identification number of each vehicle;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide a telephone number or website address that will inform the owner or lienholders of the vehicle reclamation procedures; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Indicate the date by which the vehicle must be reclaimed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="§50-2302.05">§ 50-2302.05</cite>, the mailing of the impoundment notice shall constitute service of the notice of infraction for violations of this title. The notice of infraction shall be considered issued, within the meaning of <cite path="§50-2302.05">§ 50-2302.05</cite>, on the 5th day after the impoundment notice is mailed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Director shall determine whether each impounded vehicle has been reported to law enforcement agencies as stolen and shall record the vehicle identification number for each impounded vehicle in a database format that can be accessed by law enforcement personnel.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="I|C" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-325" eff="2025-05-02" path="§125" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
