<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-301.29d</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Trade dress requirements for private vehicles-for-hire.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A private vehicle-for-hire operator shall display a trade dress approved pursuant this section at all times while the operator is logged into the private vehicle-for-hire company's digital dispatch. The trade dress shall be affixed on the windows of the vehicle-for-hire adjacent to where passengers may sit in the rear of the motor vehicle and may take the form of a removable device. All trade dress required pursuant to this section shall be submitted by a private vehicle-for-hire company to the DFHV for approval. Approved trade dress shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Sufficiently large and color contrasted so as to be readable during daylight hours at a distance of at least 50 feet; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reflective, illuminated, or otherwise patently visible in darkness.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of this section, the DFHV may require private vehicle-for-hire operators to display a standardized and clearly identifiable emblem or insignia indicating to consumers that a private vehicle-for-hire company is licensed to do business in the District. The DFHV may permit private vehicle-for-hire companies to issue such an approved insignia or certificate to operators on the Department's behalf.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A private vehicle-for-hire company shall provide an operator with trade dress compliant with the requirements of this section before the operator begins providing service for the company. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Department may establish rules allowing for a private vehicle-for-hire operator to display a temporary trade dress for a limited period of time after a vehicle-for-hire operator registers with a private vehicle-for-hire company.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97" type="History" path="§20j-4">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, <cite path="§20j-4">§ 20j-4</cite></annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-197" type="History">as added Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-197, §  2(k), 61 DCR 12430</annotation>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-03-21" eff="2025-03-21">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> provided that the amendment to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7193" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">Section 7193 of <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7193">D.C. Act 26-146</cite> repealed Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>, thus removing the applicability limitation. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(d)">§2(d) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§7193" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7193" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">Section 7193 of <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7193">D.C. Act 26-210</cite> repealed Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>, thus removing the applicability limitation. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(d)">§2(d) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7193" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
