<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-301.03</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on February 26, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§50-301.03(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§50-301.03(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“ADA” means the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 328; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Alternative fuel” means advanced fuels, which can be any materials or substances that can be used as fuels, other than conventional fuels such as fossil fuels, including biodiesel, compressed natural gas, electricity, and ethanol. The term “alternative fuel” shall also apply to hybrid vehicles that use alternative forms of power such as electricity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Capital City Plan” means the formal alphabetical and numerical pattern and layout of streets within the District’s 4 quadrants, the formal pattern and layout of avenues and circles within the District, and the formal system and pattern of addresses within the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3A)</num>
      <text>"Carrier-for-hire" means a class of transportation service by which a network of private operators, couriers, or carriers provide delivery of parcels, food, or beverages in the District for compensation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3B)</num>
      <text>"Carrier-for-hire company" means an organization, corporation, partnership, or sole proprietorship, operating in the District that uses delivery dispatch to connect customers to specific carrier-for-hire operators. The term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Includes a third-party meal delivery platform, as that term is defined in <cite path="§48-651|(6)">§ 48-651(6)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Does not include an organization, corporation, partnership, or sole proprietorship who facilitates, offers, or arranges for the delivery of goods solely by vehicles that are required to be registered with the federal motor carrier safety administration or that require a commercial driver's license to operate pursuant 49 U.S.C. § 2701 <em>et seq.</em>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Does not include an individual or entity delivering cannabis with a valid courier license issued pursuant to <cite path="§7-1671.05a">§ 7-1671.05a</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3C)</num>
      <text>"Carrier-for-hire industry" means all companies, associations, owners, operators, or any person who, by virtue of employment, contract, or office, is directly involved in providing or facilitating the provision of carrier-for-hire services within the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3D)</num>
      <text>"Carrier-for-hire operator" means an individual who is registered with a carrier-for-hire company for the purpose of being connected to a customer through the company's delivery dispatch to deliver a parcel, food, or beverage in exchange for compensation. The term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Includes a food delivery worker, as that term is defined in <cite path="§48-651|(2A)">§ 48-651(2A)</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Does not include an individual delivering parcels, food, or beverages as an employee of, or under contract with, a specific business, if the business is primarily responsible for the production of the items or goods being delivered.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3E)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Class 1" means any of the following delivery modes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Pedestrians;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Electric mobility devices;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Bicycles;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Electric bicycles;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>E-cargo bikes; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Other non-motorized means of transportation.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this paragraph the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>"E-cargo bike" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-921.27|(a)|(4)">§ 50-921.27(a)(4)</cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>"Electric bicycle" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-921.27|(a)|(5)">§ 50-921.27(a)(5)</cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>"Electric mobility device" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-2201.02|(6A)">§ 50-2201.02(6A)</cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3F)</num>
      <text>"Class 2" means an electric-powered motor vehicle that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Has a seat or saddle for the use of the operator and is designed to travel on no more than 3 wheels in contact with the ground;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is a motor-driven cycle or a motorcycle, as those terms are defined in 18 DCMR § 9901.1; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is not a Class 1 delivery mode.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3G)</num>
      <text>"Class 3" means a motor vehicle powered by an internal-combustion engine that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Has a seat or saddle for the use of the operator and is designed to travel on no more than 3 wheels in contact with the ground;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is a motor-driven cycle or motorcycle, as those terms are defined in 18 DCMR § 9901.1; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is not a Class 1 or Class 2 delivery mode.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3H)</num>
      <text>"Class 4" means all motor vehicles not classified as Class 1, 2, or 3.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3I)</num>
      <text>"Customer" means an individual purchasing and requesting the delivery of a parcel, food, or beverage, who is connected to a specific carrier-for-hire operator by a carrier-for-hire company's delivery dispatch.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“CNG” means compressed natural gas.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“CNG vehicle” means an automobile powered by compressed natural gas.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Committee” means the Vehicle-for-Hire Accessibility Advisory Committee established by <cite path="§50-301.25">§ 50-301.25</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8A)</num>
      <text>“Digital dispatch” means the hardware and software applications and networks, including mobile phone applications, which passengers and operators use to provide public and private vehicle-for-hire service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8A-i)</num>
      <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of For-Hire-Vehicles.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8B)</num>
      <text>“Dispatch” means the traditional methods of pre-arranging vehicle-for-hire service, including through telephone or radio.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>“DDOE” means the District Department of the Environment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A)</num>
      <text>"DFHV" means the Department of For-Hire Vehicles established by <cite path="§50-301.04">§ 50-301.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A-i)</num>
      <text>"Delivery mode" means the means of transportation used by a carrier-for-hire operator to provide delivery service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A-ii)</num>
      <text>"DFHV" means the Department of For-Hire Vehicles established by <cite path="§50-301.04">§ 50-301.04</cite></text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A-iii)</num>
      <text>"Digital dispatch" means the hardware and software applications and networks, including mobile phone applications, which passengers and operators use to provide public and private vehicle-for-hire service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A-iv)</num>
      <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of For-Hire-Vehicles.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9A-v)</num>
      <text>"Dispatch" means the traditional methods of pre-arranging vehicle-for-hire service, including through telephone or radio.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9B)</num>
      <text>"FHVAC" means the For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council established by <cite path="§50-301.10a">§ 50-301.10a</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>“Fund” means the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund established by <cite path="§50-301.20">§ 50-301.20</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>“GPS” means Global Positioning Satellite.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>“Hospitality industry” means any person or entity involved in the operation, management, support, or ownership of a restaurant, catering business, hotel business, conference business, travel business, tourism business, tour business, or tour guide business.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>“Industry member” means a person experienced in the transportation or hospitality industry.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>“Limousine” means a public vehicle-for-hire that operates exclusively through advanced registration, charges exclusively on the basis of time, and shall not accept street hails.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14A)</num>
      <text>"Motor vehicle" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§50-2201.02|(11)">§ 50-2201.02(11)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15A)</num>
      <text>"ORPP" means the Office of Regulatory Policy and Planning established by <cite path="§50-301.06">§ 50-301.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15B)</num>
      <text>"OCS" means the Office of Client Services established by <cite path="§50-301.06">§ 50-301.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15C)</num>
      <text>"OCE" means the Office of Compliance and Enforcement established by <cite path="§50-301.06">§ 50-301.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15D)</num>
      <text>"OHCR" means the Office of Hearings and Conflict Resolution established by <cite path="§50-301.06">§ 50-301.06</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>“Passenger surcharge” means a fee assessed to passengers for each public vehicle-for-hire ride in an amount not less than 50 cents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16A)</num>
      <text>“Private vehicle-for-hire” means a class of transportation service by which a network of private vehicle-for-hire operators in the District provides transportation to passengers to whom the private vehicle-for-hire operators are connected by digital dispatch.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16B)</num>
      <text>“Private vehicle-for-hire company” means an organization, including a corporation, partnership, or sole proprietorship, operating in the District that uses digital dispatch to connect passengers to a network of private vehicle-for-hire operators.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16C)</num>
      <text>"Private vehicle-for-hire operator" means an individual who utilizes the digital dispatch of a private vehicle-for-hire company to operate a motor vehicle to provide transportation to passengers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>“Public vehicle-for-hire” means a class of transportation service by motor vehicle for hire in the District, including a taxicab, limousine, or sedan-class vehicle, that provides for-hire service exclusively using operators and vehicles licensed pursuant to this subchapter and <cite path="§47-2829">§ 47-2829</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>“Sedan-class vehicle” means a public vehicle-for-hire that operates exclusively through digital dispatch, charges on the basis of time and distance, except for trips to airports, and other point-to-point trips based on well-traveled routes or event-related trips such as sporting events, which may be charged on a flat-fee basis, and shall not accept street hails.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab” means a class of public vehicle-for-hire that may be hired by dispatch, digital dispatch, or hailed on the street, and for which the fare charged is calculated by a DFHV-approved meter with uniform rates determined by the DFHV; provided, that a taxicab hired by a passenger through digital dispatch may use rates set by the company that operates the digital dispatch pursuant to the requirements of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab association” means a group of taxicab owners organized for the purpose of engaging in the business of taxicab transportation for common benefits regarding operation, logo or insignia. An association must have a minimum of 20 taxicabs having a uniform logo or insignia and having unified control by ownership or by association.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab company” means any person, partnership, or corporation engaging in the business of owning and operating a fleet or fleets of taxicabs having a uniform logo or insignia. A company must have a minimum of 20 taxicabs having a uniform logo or insignia and having unified control by ownership or by the company.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(24)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab fleet” means a group of 20 or more taxicabs having a uniform logo or insignia and having unified control by ownership or by association.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(25)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab industry” means all taxicab companies, associations, owners, and operators, or any person who by virtue of employment or office is directly involved in the provision of taxicab services within the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(26)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab operator” means a person operating or licensed to operate a taxicab in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(27)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab owner” means a person, corporation, partnership, or association that holds the legal title to a taxicab that is required to be registered in the District. If a taxicab is the subject of an agreement for the conditional sale or lease with right of purchase upon performance of the condition stated in the agreement and with an immediate right of possession vested in the conditional vendee or lessee, or if a mortgagor of a taxicab is entitled to possession, the conditional vendee, lessee, or mortgagor shall be considered the owner for the purpose of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(28)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab rate structure” means the rates, fares, charges, and methodologies used to determine the price of taxicab street-hail service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(29)</num>
      <text>“Taxicab service” means passenger transportation service originating in the District in which the passenger directs the points between which the service is to be provided, the service is provided at a time chosen by the passenger, and, when hailed on the street, the fare and fees for which are prescribed by the DFHV.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(29A)</num>
      <text>"Trade dress" means a unique marketing logo, insignia, or emblem for display on a vehicle that identifies, distinguishes, and is substantially inseparable from the source of a product or service, using a specific style to differentiate from competitors.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(30)</num>
      <text>“Underserved area” means a designated zone, as determined by the DFHV, with an established need for greater taxicab service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(30A)</num>
      <text>“Vehicle-for-hire industry” means all public and private vehicles-for-hire, including companies, associations, owners, operators, or any person who, by virtue of employment or office, is directly involved in providing public or private vehicle-for-hire services within the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(30B)</num>
      <text>“Vehicle inspection officer” means a District employee trained in the laws, rules, and regulations governing public and private vehicle-for-hire and carrier-for-hire service and carrier-for-hire service to ensure the proper provision of service and to support safety through street enforcement efforts, including traffic stops of public and private vehicles-for-hire and carriers-for-hire, pursuant to protocol prescribed under this subchapter and by regulation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(31)</num>
      <text>“Washington Metropolitan Area” means the area encompassed by the District; Montgomery County, Prince George’s County, and Frederick County in Maryland; Arlington County, Fairfax County, Loudon County, and Prince William County, and the cities of Alexandria, Fairfax, Falls Church, Manassas, and Manassas Park in Virginia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(32)</num>
      <text>“Wheelchair-accessible vehicle” means a vehicle compliant with the ADA that accommodates a passenger using a wheelchair or other personal mobility device who needs a ramp or lift to enter or exit the vehicle. The vehicle must comply with the provisions of 49 C.F.R. Part 38.1 — 38.39.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite> provided, in part, that §§ 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the act shall apply as of March 10, 2015.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7017 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7007 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97" type="History" path="§4">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, § 4, 33 DCR 703</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-165" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-165, § 3(a), 33 DCR 6705</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 10(ii)(1), 44 DCR 1730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-184" type="History">Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(c), 59 DCR 9431</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-270" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 2(a), 60 DCR 1717</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-197" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-197, § 2(a), 61 DCR 12430</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Taxicab Service Improvement Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-403, July 24, 2012,  59 DCR 9116).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite> added (8A), (8B), (16A), (16B), (16C), (30A), and (30B); rewrote (17); repealed (18) and (19); rewrote (21); substituted “taxicab street-hail service” for “taxicab service” in (28); and substituted “and, when hailed on the street, the fare" for “and the fare” in (29).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> substituted “through digital dispatch, charges on the basis of time and distance, except for trips to airports, and other point-to-point trips based on well-traveled routes or event-related trips such as sporting events, which may be charged on a flat-fee basis” for “through dispatch, charges exclusively on the basis of time and distance” in (20).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 50-303.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1703.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§22-404.02">§ 22-404.02</cite>, <cite path="§22-404.03">§ 22-404.03</cite>, and <cite path="§50-2201.03">§ 50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Certificates of title for motor vehicles and trailers, excise tax exemptions, “taxis” and “taxicabs” defined, see <cite path="§50-2201.03">§ 50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(7)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(c)|(8)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-242" eff="2017-04-07" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-224" eff="2019-02-22" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-12" doc="D.C. Law 24-147" eff="2022-07-12" path="§164" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-584" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-10-17" eff="2022-10-17">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-584" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Emergency Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Act 24-584, Oct. 17, 2022, 69 DCR 012718)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-10-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-584" eff="2022-10-17" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-227" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2022-12-21" eff="2022-12-21">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-227" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2022 (D.C. Law 24-227, Dec. 21, 2022, 69 DCR 13987)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-12-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-227" eff="2022-12-21" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-195" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-07-27" eff="2023-07-27">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-195" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-195, July 27, 2023, 70 DCR 10737)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 25-195" eff="2023-07-27" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-277" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-10-25" eff="2023-10-25">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-277" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Act 25-277, Oct. 25, 2023, 70 DCR 14482)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-10-25" doc="D.C. Act 25-277" eff="2023-10-25" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 25-74" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-11-28" eff="2023-11-28">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-74" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2023 (D.C. Law 25-74, Nov. 28, 2023, 70 DCR 13809)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2023-11-28" doc="D.C. Law 25-74" eff="2023-11-28" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-493" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-06-26" eff="2024-06-26">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-493" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-493, June 26, 2024, 71 DCR 7600)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-06-26" doc="D.C. Act 25-493" eff="2024-06-26" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§6102|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-07-15" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§6102|(a)">§ 6102(a) of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-07-15" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§6102|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 25-205" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-04" eff="2024-09-04">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-205" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Law 25-205, Sept. 4, 2024, 71 DCR 9325)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-04" doc="D.C. Law 25-205" eff="2024-09-04" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§6102|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-03-21" eff="2025-03-21">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> provided that the amendment to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(7)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-301" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(a)|(7)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-62" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-04-24" eff="2025-04-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-62" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-62, Apr. 24, 2025, 72 DCR 5330)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-04-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-62" eff="2025-04-24" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-07-16" doc="D.C. Law 26-18" eff="2025-07-16" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-07-16" doc="D.C. Law 26-18" eff="2025-07-16" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-07-16" doc="D.C. Law 26-18" eff="2025-07-16" path="§2|(a)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 26-18" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-07-16" eff="2025-07-16">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-18" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Department of For-Hire Vehicles Delivery Vehicle Traffic Enforcement Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Law 26-18, July 16, 2025, 72 DCR 6114)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7193" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">Section 7193 of <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7193">D.C. Act 26-146</cite> repealed Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>, thus removing the applicability limitation. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(a)">§2(a) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§7193" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7193" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">Section 7193 of <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7193">D.C. Act 26-210</cite> repealed Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§4">D.C. Law 25-301</cite>, thus removing the applicability limitation. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-301" path="§2|(a)">§2(a) of D.C. Law 25-301</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7193" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-212" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-212" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-212" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-212" path="§2">§ 2 of Private Vehicle-for-Hire Operator Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-212, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
