<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.29</num>
  <heading proof="needed">RFK Transportation Improvement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Transportation Improvement Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Excess RFK Campus Infrastructure Funds up to $20 million annually, pursuant to section 2052(d)(2) of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825), shall be deposited into the Transportation Improvement Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money in the Transportation Improvement Fund shall be used to support public-transit related improvements for the RFK Campus, including Metrorail and Metrobus, related infrastructure, Metrorail stations and roadways, and investments to improve transportation access to the RFK Campus; provided, that any roadway improvements are directly related to an improvement to public transit access on the RFK Campus.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Expenditures for the purposes set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection may include both operating and capital costs, but may not be expended for the maintenance or construction of new roadways unless the expenditure is directly related to an improvement to public transit access.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Transportation Improvement Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Transportation Improvement Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term "RFK Campus" shall have the meaning set forth in <cite path="§10-1605.01|(18)">§ 10-1605.01(18)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9u">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9u</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9u" display="false">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9u</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§19" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§19|includes|9u">§ 9u of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§19" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§19" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
