<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1281.04</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Privilege to practice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To exercise the privilege to practice under the terms and provisions of the Compact, the Licensee shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Hold a license in the home state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have a valid United States Social Security number or National Practitioner Identifier;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be eligible for a privilege to practice in any member state in accordance with subsections (d), (g), and (h) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have not had any encumbrance or restriction against any license or privilege to practice within the previous 2 years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Notify the Commission that the licensee is seeking the privilege to practice within a remote state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Pay any applicable fees, including any state fee, for the privilege to practice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Meet any continuing competence or continuing education requirements established by the home state;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Meet any jurisprudence requirements established by the remote state in which the licensee is seeking a privilege to practice; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Report to the Commission any adverse action, encumbrance, or restriction on a license taken by any non-member state within 30 days from the date the action is taken.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The privilege to practice is valid until the expiration date of the home state license; provided, that the licensee shall comply with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section to maintain the privilege to practice in the remote state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A licensee providing professional counseling in a remote state under the privilege to practice shall adhere to the laws and regulations of the remote state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A licensee providing professional counseling services in a remote state is subject to that state's regulatory authority. A remote state may, in accordance with due process and that state's laws, remove a licensee's privilege to practice in the remote state for a specific period of time, impose fines, or take any other necessary actions to protect the health and safety of its citizens. The licensee may be ineligible for a privilege to practice in any member state until the specific time for removal has passed and all fines are paid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a home state license is encumbered, the licensee shall lose the privilege to practice in any remote state until the following occurs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The home state license is no longer encumbered; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have not had any encumbrance or restriction against any license or privilege to practice within the previous 2 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Once an encumbered license in the home state is restored to good standing, the licensee shall meet the requirements of subsection (a) of this section to obtain a privilege to practice in any remote state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If a licensee's privilege to practice in any remote state is removed, the individual may lose the privilege to practice in all other remote states until the following occur:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The specific period of time for which the privilege to practice was removed has ended;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All fines have been paid; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have not had any encumbrance or restriction against any license or privilege to practice within the previous 2 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Once the requirements of subsection (g) of this section have been met, the licensee shall meet the requirements in subsection (a) of this section to obtain a privilege to practice in a remote state.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-238" eff="2024-12-17" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-238" eff="2024-12-17" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
