<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1631.05</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on April 3, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§38-1631.05(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Institution, conference, and athletic association involvement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An institution, conference, or athletic association may assist a college athlete:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In evaluating the permissibility of name, image, or likeness activity, including compliance with the law and institution, conference, and association rules;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>With the disclosure requirements of <cite path="§38-1631.06">§ 38-1631.06</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By providing a good-faith evaluation of a name, image, or likeness agent or third party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>With selecting, arranging for, or providing payment to a name, image, or likeness agent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>With selecting, arranging for, or collecting payment from a third party engaged in specific name, image, or likeness agreements with a college athlete or athletes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An institution may permit a college athlete to use the institution's facilities for name, image, or likeness activity under the same terms and conditions as other students at the institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An institution, conference, or athletic association shall educate a college athlete about name, image, or likeness compensation, agreements, and activity by offering financial literacy and life skills programming to college athletes. At a minimum, the programming should include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information concerning student loan, financial aid, and debt management;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Time management skills necessary for success as a college athlete and an overview of available academic support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Budgeting based on cost of attendance, living expenses, and scholarship resources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An explanation of services offered by and guidance for accessing banks and basic banking products;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An introduction to income taxes, including income earned as an independent contractor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Warnings about payday and predatory lending practices.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This subsection shall not be construed to place an obligation on an institution to provide individualized tax or legal guidance to college athletes seeking or earning name, image, or likeness compensation.</text>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-02-23" doc="D.C. Law 24-245" eff="2023-02-23" path="§215" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-69" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2025-05-19" eff="2025-05-19">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-69" path="§2">§ 2 of Uniform College Athlete Name, Image, or Likeness Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-69, May 19, 2025, 72 DCR 6112)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-05-19" doc="D.C. Act 26-69" eff="2025-05-19" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-120" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2025-07-21" eff="2025-07-21">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-120" path="§2">§ 2 of Uniform College Athlete Name, Image, or Likeness Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-120, July 21, 2025, 72 DCR 8181)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-07-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-120" eff="2025-07-21" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-08-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" eff="2025-08-21" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-08-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" eff="2025-08-21" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-08-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" eff="2025-08-21" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-08-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" eff="2025-08-21" path="§2|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-08-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" eff="2025-08-21" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 26-26" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2025-08-21" eff="2025-08-21">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-26" path="§2">§ 2 of Uniform College Athlete Name, Image, or Likeness Temporary Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Law 26-26, Aug. 21, 2025, 72 DCR 7559)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
