<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2264</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§38-2264(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Achieving competency in structured literacy instruction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An LEA shall require each of its teachers to successfully complete an OSSE-approved structured literacy training or to demonstrate competency in structured literacy instruction within a year of the teacher's hire or by the start of the school year identified in table 1 of this paragraph, whichever is later:</text>
      <text>
        <table>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th colspan="2">Table 1: Structured Literacy Competency Requirement Schedule</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <th>Teacher Grade Level</th>
              <th>School Year</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>Kindergarten</td>
              <td>2026-2027</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>First</td>
              <td>2027-2028</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Second</td>
              <td>2028-2029</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Third</td>
              <td>2029-2030</td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
      </text>
      <text>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Teachers may fulfill the requirement to complete an approved structured literacy training or demonstrate competency in structured literacy instruction by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Providing proof of successful completion of an OSSE-approved structured literacy training for the appropriate instructional cohort; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Providing proof of receiving a passing score on a structured literacy competency assessment or evaluation that OSSE identified or developed.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A teacher who is employed by an LEA as of the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Act of 2024, passed on 2nd reading on June 25, 2024 (Enrolled version of Bill 25-784), shall be deemed to have successfully completed an OSSE-approved structured literacy training or demonstrated competency in structured literacy instruction by the start of the 2026-2027 school year if the teacher successfully completed an OSSE-approved structured literacy training for the appropriate instructional cohort or received a passing score on a structured literacy competency assessment or evaluation that OSSE identified or developed between January 2019 and August 2026.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>During School Years 2025-2026 through 2029-2030, including summers, LEAs shall dedicate at least 10 hours of professional development time, scheduled during regularly contracted work hours, for teachers who intend to complete structured literacy training and have not already done so to participate in such training; provided, that the LEA may designate the time and place for the training.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>LEAs shall compensate kindergarten teachers, and, subject to the availability of funding, all other teachers, for time spent outside of regularly contracted work hours to complete an OSSE-approved structured literacy training.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>OSSE may issue rules prescribing additional requirements for educators employed by an LEA to complete approved structured literacy trainings or demonstrate competency in structured literacy instruction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to available funding, by April 1, 2026, OSSE shall establish and administer a grant program to reimburse LEAs for costs, including payments to teachers and assessment fees incurred in meeting the requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning October 31, 2026, and by October 31 of each year thereafter, DCPS and each public charter LEA shall send a letter to OSSE reporting whether each school under the LEA's authority has complied with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section by October 5 of the reporting year.  If a school has failed to comply, the LEA shall state the name of the school, the deficiency, and the timeline for curing the deficiency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>OSSE shall make the compliance letters received pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection publicly available within 15 business days after receiving them.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§4115">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 4115</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-167" type="History" path="§4115" display="false">Sept. 21, 2022, D.C. Law 24-167, § 4115</annotation>
    <annotation app="2022-09-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-167" eff="2022-09-21" path="IV|L" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4172|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-07-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-506" path="§4172|(b)|includes|4115">§ 4115 of Fiscal Year 2025 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-506, July 15, 2024, 71 DCR 8406)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Act 25-506" eff="2024-07-15" path="§4172|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§4172|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§4112" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§4112">§ 4112 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§4112" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(b)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(b)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4112|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§4112" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§4112">§ 4112 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
