<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-651.03a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Seizure action plan and training requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The responsible person shall submit a seizure action plan to the school for a student diagnosed with a seizure disorder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A valid seizure action plan shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A written statement or authorization, signed by the student's health care provider, that states:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name of the student;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Emergency contact information for the responsible person, or, if the student is 18 years of age or older, another adult suitable to serve as an emergency contact;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Contact information for the health care provider;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The name, purpose, and prescribed dosage of the seizure treatment prescribed to the student;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The method of administration for the seizure treatment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The frequency that the seizure treatment is to be administered;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The symptoms necessitating administration of the seizure treatment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>The possible side effects of the seizure treatment as listed on the label;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Special instructions or emergency procedures; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>In the case of self-administered seizure treatment, confirmation that the student has been instructed in the proper technique of self-administration of the seizure treatment and has demonstrated the ability to self-administer the seizure treatment effectively;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Written authorization, signed by the responsible person, that states:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A trained employee or agent of the school may administer seizure treatment to the student in accordance with the student's seizure action plan;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of self-administration, the student may possess and self-administer the seizure treatment in accordance with the student's seizure action plan; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The name of the student and their seizure action plan may be distributed to school staff or agents who may encounter the student during their time at school; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Written acknowledgment that the District, a school, or an employee or agent of a school, who has received training in the administration of seizure treatment, shall be immune from civil liability for the good-faith performance of responsibilities under <cite path="38|6|IV">this subchapter</cite>; except, that no immunity shall extend to criminal acts, intentional wrongdoing, gross negligence, or wanton or willful misconduct.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any school staff or agent who receives personally identifiable health information through a seizure action plan pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall keep this information confidential.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning on June 1, 2025, the Department of Health shall offer a voluntary training on seizure awareness at least 3 times during each school year for school personnel and agents, which shall include recognition of the signs and symptoms of seizures and the appropriate steps to be taken to respond to those symptoms.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Schools shall notify, at minimum, all school personnel with direct contact with students with seizure action plans of the availability of the training offered under subsection (d) of this section and authorize personnel to attend this training.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-272" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
