<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-851.02</num>
  <heading proof="needed">LEA requirements for a personal wireless communication device policy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than 15 days before the start of the 2026-2027 School Year, each LEA serving students enrolled in grades K-12 shall adopt and implement a personal wireless communication device policy that prohibits K-12 students from, at a minimum, possessing a personal wireless communication device on school premises at any time during the full school day.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An LEA's personal wireless communication device policy may include exemptions for a student possessing a personal wireless communication device for specific educational purposes and to manage a student's health care needs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each LEA's personal wireless communication device policy shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establish consequences if a student violates the policy; provided, that the consequences shall be consistent with <cite path="ยง38-236.04">ยง 38-236.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establish a process and timeline for the LEA to assess whether the policy is working and how to refine it;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be published on the LEA's website no later than 15 days before the start of each school year for which the policy is in effect, and that mid-year modifications shall be published no later than 15 days before being effective;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Be communicated to all enrolled families before the first day of school; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Be communicated to all LEA employees, contractors, and volunteers who have contact with students during school hours.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each LEA's personal wireless communication device policy shall require each school in the LEA to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify how a parent or guardian of an enrolled student should communicate urgent information to their child during the full school day;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify how the school will communicate with families in cases of emergency; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identify appropriate storage for students' personal wireless communication devices during the full school day.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-09-10" doc="D.C. Law 26-39" eff="2025-09-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-09-10" doc="D.C. Law 26-39" eff="2025-09-10" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
