<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-851.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="38|8D">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Full school day" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="ยง38-201|(2B)">ยง 38-201(2B)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Health care needs" means specific medical requirements or disability- or health-related supports that are documented by a licensed medical provider with the LEA and that require the use of a personal wireless communication device for monitoring a medical condition, administering medication, receiving health-related alerts, receiving disability-related supports, or communicating with medical personnel or caregivers regarding the student's health during the school day.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"LEA" means local education agency, which is the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual public charter school or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Personal wireless communication device" means a cellular phone, tablet computer, laptop computer, or gaming device that is not owned or provided by the school.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Possessing" means carrying or holding an item on one's person but does not include carrying or holding an item in a backpack, purse, handbag, or other personal carryall.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-09-10" doc="D.C. Law 26-39" eff="2025-09-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-09-10" doc="D.C. Law 26-39" eff="2025-09-10" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
