<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1671.06i</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Grounds for protest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A protest against a medical cannabis retailer license by persons with standing under <cite path="§7-1671.06g">§ 7-1671.06g</cite> shall be on the basis of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A violation of <cite path="7|16B">this chapter</cite> by the applicant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A violation of civil law by the applicant that is directly related to the operation of the business or establishment for which the license is sought; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Vehicular and pedestrian safety.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The ABC Board shall determine whether a violation of civil law is directly related to the operation of the business or establishment for which the license is sought by considering the totality of the following factors:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whether specific elements of the violation are directly related to the specific duties and responsibilities of the license; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any evidence produced by the applicant concerning the applicant's fitness, including the length of time that has elapsed since the violation and mitigating circumstances.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The ABC Board may issue a license, approve the renewal of a license, or approve the transfer of a medical cannabis retailer license to a new location without a hearing on the protest if the ABC Board finds that the basis of the protest lacks substance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 13-315" path="§7i">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 7i</annotation>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 13-315" path="§7i" display="false">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 7i</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-627" path="§4|(h)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-12-17" eff="2024-11-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-627" path="§4|(h)|includes|7i">§ 7i of Medical Cannabis Clarification and Program Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-627, Nov. 13, 2024, 71 DCR 14129)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Act 25-627" eff="2024-11-13" path="§4|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-255" eff="2024-12-17" path="§4|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
