<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-1671.06g</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Standing to file protest against a retailer license.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§7-1671.05a">§ 7-1671.05a</cite> regarding protests against unlicensed establishments that applied for licenses prior to January 30, 2024, the following persons may protest the issuance of a license, the renewal of a license, or the transfer of a medical cannabis retailer license to a new location:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A property owner or commercial tenant whose property abuts where the establishment is or will be located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A property owner or commercial tenant whose property is located directly across the street from where the establishment is or will be located; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A daycare center located within 400 feet of where the establishment is or will be located, or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any affected ANC.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person objecting under subsection (a) of this section to the approval of an application shall notify the ABC Board in writing of his or her intention to object and the specific grounds for the objection within the protest period.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 13-315" path="§7g">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 7g</annotation>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 13-315" path="§7g" display="false">Feb. 25, 2010, D.C. Law 13-315, § 7g</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 25-627" path="§4|(h)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-12-17" eff="2024-11-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 25-627" path="§4|(h)|includes|7g">§ 7g of Medical Cannabis Clarification and Program Enforcement Emergency Amendment Act of 2024 (D.C. Act 25-627, Nov. 13, 2024, 71 DCR 14129)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Act 25-627" eff="2024-11-13" path="§4|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 25-255" eff="2024-12-17" path="§4|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
