<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2071.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§7-2071.01(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Accessible” means providing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The program’s written materials in Spanish and English, and in other languages when required by Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 252; 42 U.S.C. § 2000d et seq.) (“Title VI”), or District law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Interpreters to communicate with consumers in Spanish, and in other languages when required by Title VI or District law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>TTY services and other accommodations for individuals with disabilities in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. § 12101 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Consumer” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An uninsured resident of the District, including residents enrolled in the HealthCare Alliance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An individual covered by a health benefits plan in the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>An individual applying for, or receiving public benefits, in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>"DHCF" means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3B)</num>
    <text>"DHS" means the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Health benefits plan” means a group or individual insurance policy or contract, medical or hospital service agreement, membership or subscription contract, or similar group arrangement provided by an insurer, or subcontracting facility of an insurer, or an employer for the purpose of providing, paying for, or reimbursing expenses for health-related services. The term “health benefits plan” shall include health coverage provided through a government program, including Medicaid. The term “health benefits plan” shall not include disability income or accident-only insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Health Care and Public Benefits Ombudsman” or “Ombudsman” means the individual responsible for running the Health Care and Public Benefits Ombudsman Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Health Care and Public Benefits Ombudsman Program" or "Ombudsman Program" means the program established by the District to counsel and assist:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Uninsured District residents and individuals insured by health benefits plans in the District regarding matters pertaining to their health care coverage; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Individuals applying for or receiving public benefits in the District regarding matters pertaining to their public benefits coverage including those adversely impacted by a public benefits determination.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Health care services” means items or services provided under the supervision of a physician or other person trained or licensed to render health care necessary for the prevention, care, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease, pain, injury, deformity, or other physical or mental condition, including the following: pre-admission, outpatient, inpatient, and post-discharge care; home care; physician’s care; nursing care; medical care provided by interns or residents in training; other paramedical care; ambulance service and care; bed and board; drugs; supplies; appliances; equipment; laboratory services; any form of diagnostic imaging or therapeutic radiological services; and services mandated under <cite path="31|31">Chapter 31 of Title 31</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>"Public benefits" means a program administered by the Economic Security Administration of DHS, including the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program ("SNAP") and Temporary Assistance for Needy Families ("TANF") program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-331" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-331, § 2, 52 DCR 1981</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5212|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5212|(a)">§ 5212(a) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§5212|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(a)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5212|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5212|(a)">§ 5212(a) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
