<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2071.10</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§7-2071.10(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Requirements for health benefits plans, HealthCare Alliance, and the Department of Human Services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Health benefits plans and the HealthCare Alliance shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Include in their marketing and membership materials information regarding the availability of the Ombudsman Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Send annually to their members notification of the availability of the Ombudsman Program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide members the telephone number of the Ombudsman Program upon request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A health benefits plan may use the one-page, easy-to-read flyer developed by the Ombudsman Program to describe its services to meet the notice requirements under subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>DHS shall display prominently on its website, in all public benefits applications, in all official materials conveying information about public benefits, and in each of its service centers, a notice of information regarding the availability of, and services provided by, the Ombudsman Program, including the Ombudsman Program's telephone number, email address, and website.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-331" type="History" path="§11">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-331, § 11, 52 DCR 1981</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5212|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5212|(g)">§ 5212(g) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§5212|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(g)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5212|(g)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5212|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5212|(g)">§ 5212(g) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
