<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2165</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Remedies.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In an action under <cite path="7|21D">this chapter</cite>, a prevailing plaintiff may recover:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The greater of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Economic and noneconomic damages proximately caused by the defendant's disclosure or threatened disclosure, including damages for emotional distress whether or not accompanied by other damages; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Statutory damages not to exceed $10,000 against each defendant found liable under <cite path="7|21D">this chapter</cite> for all disclosures and threatened disclosures by the defendant of which the plaintiff knew or reasonably should have known when filing the action or which became known during the pendency of the action. In determining the amount of statutory damages under this subparagraph, consideration must be given to the age of the parties at the time of the disclosure or threatened disclosure, the number of disclosures or threatened disclosures made by the defendant, the breadth of distribution of the image by the defendant, and other exacerbating or mitigating factors;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to any monetary gain made by the defendant from disclosure of the intimate image; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Punitive damages.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In an action under <cite path="7|21D">this chapter</cite>, the court may award a prevailing plaintiff:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reasonable attorney's fees and costs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Additional relief, including injunctive relief.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text><cite path="7|21D">This chapter</cite> does not affect a right or remedy available under law of the District other than this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-268" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-268" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง6" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
