<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2162</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Civil action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Harm" includes physical harm, economic harm, and emotional distress whether or not accompanied by physical or economic harm.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Private" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Created or obtained under circumstances in which a depicted individual had a reasonable expectation of privacy; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Made accessible through theft, bribery, extortion, fraud, false pretenses, voyeurism, or exceeding authorized access to an account, message, file, device, resource, or property.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in <cite path="ยง7-2163">ยง 7-2163</cite>, a depicted individual who is identifiable and who suffers harm from a person's intentional disclosure or threatened disclosure of an intimate image that was private without the depicted individual's consent has a cause of action against the person if the person knew or acted with reckless disregard for whether:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The depicted individual did not consent to the disclosure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The intimate image was private; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The depicted individual was identifiable.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The following conduct by a depicted individual does not establish by itself that the individual consented to the disclosure of the intimate image which is the subject of an action under <cite path="7|21D">this chapter</cite> or that the individual lacked a reasonable expectation of privacy:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Consent to creation of the image; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Previous consensual disclosure of the image.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A depicted individual who does not consent to the sexual conduct or uncovering of the part of the body depicted in an intimate image of the individual retains a reasonable expectation of privacy even if the image was created when the individual was in a public place.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-268" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-268" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
