<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-743.11</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Advisory Committee on Certified Nurse Aides and Nursing Assistive Personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Committee on Certified Nurse Aides and Nursing Assistive Personnel ("Committee"), which shall consist of the following 5 members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual who has experience working as a home-health aide or a certified nurse aide;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two representatives of providers licensed in the District to provide certified nurse aide services, one of which shall represent home-health agencies and one of which shall represent certified nurse aide providers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One representative from entities approved to train certified nurse aides; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>One representative from the Department of Health.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall develop and submit recommendations to the Board of Nursing for the certification of certified nurse aides. The guidelines shall set forth the education and competency-based standards for certification, consistent with the requirements established under 42 C.F.R. § 483.152 and 42 C.F.R. § 484.80.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall review barriers to the development and support of on-the-job training programs and registered apprenticeship programs of certified nurse aides, including certified nurse aides seeking advance credentials, and shall make recommendations on eliminating such barriers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Committee shall sunset 2 years after its first meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4949b">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4949b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-12-12" doc="D.C. Law 25-232" eff="2024-12-12" path="§3" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
