<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-106.02a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Prohibited conduct – student loan servicers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No student loan servicer shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Directly or indirectly employ any scheme, device, or artifice to defraud a student loan borrower;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Directly or indirectly employ any scheme, device, or artifice to mislead a student loan borrower;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Engage in any unfair or deceptive practice toward any person or misrepresent or omit any material information in connection with the servicing of a student education loan, including an abusive act and practice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Obtain property by fraud;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Obtain property by misrepresentation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Misapply student education loan payments to the outstanding balance of a student education loan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide inaccurate information to a credit bureau, harming a student loan borrower's creditworthiness;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Fail to report both the favorable and unfavorable payment history of the student loan borrower to a nationally recognized consumer credit bureau at least annually if the student loan servicer regularly reports information to a credit bureau;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Refuse to communicate with an authorized representative of the student loan borrower who provides a written authorization signed by the student loan borrower; except, that the student loan servicer may adopt procedures reasonably related to verifying that the representative is authorized to act on behalf of the student loan borrower;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Make a false statement or make an omission of a material fact in connection with any information or report filed with a governmental agency or in connection with any investigation conducted by the Commissioner or another governmental agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Fail to respond within 15 business days to a communication from the Department, or the Office of the Attorney General, or within such shorter reasonable period of time as may be requested by the Department or the Attorney General; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Fail to respond within 15 business days to a consumer complaint submitted to the student loan servicer by the Department or the Office of the Attorney General.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A student loan servicer may request additional time to respond to the complaint, up to a maximum of 45 business days, provided that the request is accompanied by an explanation as to why additional time is reasonable and necessary.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-268" type="History" path="§7b-1">May 21, 1997, D.C. Law 11-268, § 7b-1</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-11-27" doc="D.C. Law 25-219" eff="2024-11-27" path="§2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
