<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3834.03a</num>
  <heading>Coverage of additional reproductive services. </heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual health plan or group health plan shall provide coverage for abortion and abortion-care services, including follow-up services, to an enrollee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No individual health plan or group health plan shall impose any deductible, coinsurance, copayment, or other cost-sharing requirement, on an enrollee for the coverage required by this section; except, that an individual health plan or group health plan may require a deductible, co-payment, or cost sharing for an enrollee covered by a high deductible health plan, as defined in 26 U.S.C. ยง 223(c)(2), if required by federal law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No individual health plan or group health plan covered under subsection (a) of this section shall impose any medically unnecessary restrictions or delays on the coverage required by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Coverage for services under this section shall be provided without discrimination on the basis of age, ancestry, disability, domestic partner status, gender, gender expression, gender identity, genetic information, marital status, national origin, race, religion, sex, or sexual orientation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to health insurance coverage through Medicaid, the DC Healthcare Alliance program, or the Immigrant Children's program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-254" type="History" path="ยง5c-1">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-254, ยง 5c-1</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-305" eff="2025-03-21" path="ยง3|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
