<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1210.71</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§2-1210.71(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Establishment of the Neighborhood Prosperity Initiative.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Neighborhood Prosperity Initiative ("Initiative"), which shall be administered by the Mayor and under which the Mayor may provide, on a competitive basis, grants for commercial, non-residential components of a qualifying project to applicants that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Propose a qualifying project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have a deficit in funding for a commercial, non-residential component of the qualifying project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Agree to commence construction on the qualifying project within 18 months of the award of an Initiative grant, or within such other time period as may be established by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Agree to enter into a First Source agreement, if applicable, and a Certified Business Enterprise agreement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Agree to use a grant provided under the Initiative only for the commercial, non-residential components of the project for which the grant is provided.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subtitle, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Certified Business Enterprise agreement" means an agreement with the Department of Small and Local Business Development pursuant to <cite path="2|2|IX-A">subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this title</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"First Source agreement" means an agreement with the Department of Employment Services governing certain obligations of the developer pursuant to <cite path="§2-219.03">§ 2-219.03</cite> and Mayor's Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983, regarding job creation and employment generated as a result of the construction on the property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Qualifying project" means a mixed-use or retail real estate development project that is located in a:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Low-income community, as that term is defined in section 45D(e) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved December 21, 2000 (114 Stat. 2763; 26 U.S.C. § 45D(e));</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Retail Priority Area established by, or approved by the Council pursuant to, <cite path="§2-1217.73">§ 2-1217.73</cite>; provided, that the mixed-use or retail real estate development project borders on or touches along an edge of a Neighborhood Prosperity Fund boundary as established by the Mayor; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Main Street corridor supported by the Department of Small and Local Business Development; provided, that the mixed-use or retail real estate development project borders on or touches along an edge of a Neighborhood Prosperity Fund boundary as established by the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="II|B" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§2012" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2012" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2012">§ 2012 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2012" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2012">§ 2012 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§2012" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2012" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2022-07-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-536" eff="2022-07-27" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-11-03" doc="D.C. Act 24-628" eff="2022-11-03" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2022-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-196" eff="2022-12-13" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2022" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2022">§ 2022 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§2022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2022" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2022" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2022">§ 2022 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
