<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1542</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 5, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§2-1542(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Chief of Police" means the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>"Curfew hours" means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>From 11:00 p.m. every day until 6:00 a.m. on the following day;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Extended curfew hours established by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§2-1542.01">§ 2-1542.01</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Extended curfew hours in extended juvenile curfew zones established by the Chief of Police pursuant to <cite path="§2-1542.02">§ 2-1542.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Emergency” means an unforeseen combination of circumstances or the resulting state that calls for immediate action. The term “emergency” includes, but is not limited to, a fire, a natural disaster, an automobile accident, or any situation that requires immediate action to prevent serious bodily injury or loss of life.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Establishment” means any privately-owned place of business operated for a profit to which the public is invited, including, but not limited to, any place of amusement or entertainment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Guardian” means a person who, under court order, is the guardian of the person of a minor or a public or private agency with whom a minor has been placed by a court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Minor” means any person under the age of 18 years, but does not include a judicially emancipated minor or a married minor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Narcotic trafficking” means the act of engaging in any prohibited activity related to narcotic drugs or controlled substances as defined in <cite path="48|9">Chapter 9 of Title 48</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6A)</num>
    <text>"Notice of violation of curfew" means a verbal warning, authorized by an official that informs a groups of juveniles that they are violating the terms of a curfew, that they may be arrested if they continue to violate the curfew, and identifies reasonable steps that they can take to leave the area to avoid arrest.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Operator” means any individual, firm, association, partnership, or corporation that operates, manages, or conducts any establishment. The term “operator” includes the members or partners of an association or partnership and the officers of a corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Parent” means a natural parent, adoptive parent or step-parent, or any person who has legal custody by court order or marriage, or any person not less than 21 years of age who is authorized by the natural parent, adoptive parent, step-parent or custodial parent of a child to be a caretaker for the child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Public place” means any place to which the public, or a substantial group of the public, has access, and includes, but is not limited to, streets, highways, and the common areas of schools, hospitals, apartment houses, office buildings, transport facilities, and shops.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Remain” means to linger or stay or fail to leave the premises when requested to do so by a police officer or the owner, operator, or other person in control of the premises.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Serious bodily injury” means bodily injury that creates a substantial risk of death or that causes death, serious permanent disfigurement, or protracted loss or impairment of the function of any bodily member or organ.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-128">D.C. Law 12-128</cite> repealed the sunset provision in section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-48">D.C. Law 11-48</cite>, which provided that D.C. Law 11-48 shall expire 2 years after its effective date. Therefore D.C. Law 11-48 remains in effect.</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See notes to <cite path="§2-1541">§ 2-1541</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 11-48</text>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3, 42 DCR 3627</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of Enhanced Crime Prevention and Abatement Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-446, July 21, 2006,  53 DCR 6477).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-2182.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3a" display="false">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3b" display="false">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3b</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-104" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-07-07" eff="2025-07-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-104" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Juvenile Curfew Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-104, July 7, 2025, 72 DCR 7691)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-07-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-104" eff="2025-07-07" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-07" eff="2025-11-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
