<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1515.04c</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Pilot Grant Programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Youth Pre-Apprenticeship Grant Pilot Program.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2026, the Department shall establish a one-year pilot grant program to provide pre-apprenticeship training services for youth detained at New Beginnings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To be eligible to participate in the pilot program, an applicant shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Hold status in good standing as:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>An accredited higher education institution;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A prior or current provider of apprenticeship programming at a Department Achievement Center; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have a demonstrated history of providing pre-apprenticeship training or apprenticeship services for youth.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The grant awardee shall provide participants with workforce skills training and evidence-based instruction that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Promotes targeted skills development in an in-demand industry sector or occupation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is conducive to work and training in a safe environment in accordance with applicable federal and District child labor laws; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Enables participants to gain:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Postsecondary education credit, as applicable; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Access to an industry-recognized apprenticeship program, as applicable, that:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Leads to a career in high-skill, high-wage, and in-demand industry sectors and occupations in the local or regional labor market;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Pays wages to participants based on a progressively increasing, clearly defined schedule of wages;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>Provides participants with services to support their persistence in and completion of the program;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(IV)</num>
            <text>Provides collaborative professional development services to workplace supervisors, mentors, teachers, counselors, and other staff to develop and maintain a well-integrated, high-performing program; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(V)</num>
            <text>Provides individualized career counseling, counseling about postsecondary education, or academic counseling.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Preference shall be made in favor of grant applicants:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Based within the District of Columbia or primarily serving residents of the District of Columbia; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>With a demonstrated history of partnership with the District of Columbia government, including receiving grant awards within the past 5 years, having current or prior MOUs with a District agency within the past 5 years, or having entered into partnerships with the Department of Employment Services.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Within 14 months of receiving a grant issued pursuant to this subsection, an awardee shall submit to the Department and the Council a report that describes, at a minimum, the:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Number of participants served, by age and Ward residence;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Services received by participants;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Outcomes by type of service rendered to participants;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Number of participants currently enrolled in postsecondary education; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Number of participants currently enrolled in apprenticeship programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Youth Recidivism Reduction Grant Pilot Program.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2026, the Department shall establish a one-year pilot grant program to support youth re-entry services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To be eligible to participate in the pilot program, an applicant shall hold status in good standing as a:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>501(c)(3) non-profit organization;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Neighborhood Family Success Center; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Other Department or Child and Family Services Agency grantee within the past five years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The grant shall fund projects that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide the following aftercare and case management services, including coordinating the delivery of services, to youth upon release from a Department secure facility:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Housing assistance;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Job training;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Conflict resolution skills training;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Assistance with coordination of school reenrollment and credit transfer;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Access to out-of-school programming, including enrollment in and transportation to afterschool activities;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Mentorship programming; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Any such other services to address identified needs for the purposes of preventing youth from committing further offenses; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Include close coordination with the Department to implement aspects of discharge and reentry plans described in <cite path="§16-2320|(i)">§ 16-2320(i)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Preference shall be granted to applicants:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Based in the District of Columbia or with a mission of primarily serving residents of the District of Columbia; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>With a demonstrated history of partnership with the District of Columbia government, including receiving District-funded grant awards within the past 5 years, having current or prior MOUs with a District agency within the past 5 years, or entering into partnerships with the Department within the past 5 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Within 14 months of receiving a grant issued pursuant to this subsection, a recipient shall submit to the Department and the Council a report that describes, at a minimum:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of youth served, by age and Ward residence;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The services received by participants;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Outcomes by type of service rendered to participants;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The number of school-aged participants who are enrolled in school or a GED program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The number of non-school-aged participants who are enrolled in postsecondary education; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The number of non-school-aged participants who are employed full or part time.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Within 14 months of issuing any grant pursuant to this subsection, the Department shall submit to the Office of the Attorney General and the Council committee with jurisdiction over the Department a report disclosing for each youth participant any known involvement with law enforcement or return to Department custody during the duration of the grant period, subject to juvenile confidentiality laws.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1515.04b" expire="2025-11-24" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 2-1515.04c, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5122|includes|104c">§ 104c of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1515.04c" applicability="2025-11-24" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1515.04c">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5122|includes|104c">§ 104c of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1515.04c" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1515.04c">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-335" type="History" path="§104c" display="false">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-335, § 104c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-335" type="History" path="§104c">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-335, § 104c</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5122" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5122|includes|104c">§ 104c of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§5122" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5122" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5122" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5122" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5122|includes|104c">§ 104c of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
