<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1542.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 5, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Temporary designations of extended juvenile curfew hour zones.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may designate any area of the District as an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, in which extended juvenile curfew hours determined by the Chief of Police shall apply, if the Chief of Police determines that the designation of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone is appropriate to protect public safety or public or private property in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, the Chief of Police shall issue an order that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The basis for the designation of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The boundaries of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The days and hours of the extended juvenile curfew hours in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone; provided, that the extended juvenile curfew hours in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall not begin earlier than 8:00 p.m., nor extend past 6:00 a.m., on any day;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Shall not remain in effect for more than 4 consecutive days, except as provided in subsection (e) of this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Shall not apply to groups of 8 or fewer individuals.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In determining whether to designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, the Chief of Police shall consider the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within the preceding 30 days, the occurrence of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Juvenile curfew violations in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Police reports of disturbances of the public peace described in <cite path="§22-1301">§ 22-1301</cite>, §§ <cite path="§22-1307">22-1307</cite>, <cite path="§22-1309">22-1309</cite>, <cite path="§22-1312">22-1312</cite>, or <cite path="§22-1318">22-1318</cite>, <cite path="§22-1321">§ 22-1321</cite>, or <cite path="§22-1322">§ 22-1322</cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Police reports of dangerous crimes, as that term is defined in <cite path="§23-1331|(3)">§ 23-1331(3)</cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Police reports of crimes of violence, as that term is defined in <cite path="§23-1331|(4)">§ 23-1331(4)</cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Police reports of destruction of or damage to public or private property in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Intelligence or verifiable information indicative of an intent of 9 or more juveniles to gather in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone in such a manner that is likely to result in substantial harm to the public safety, the safety of those gathering, or substantial damage to public or private property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any other verifiable information from which the Chief of Police may ascertain that public safety or public or private property in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone is likely to be endangered by the presence of unaccompanied juveniles in the extended juvenile curfew hours zones.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone the Chief of Police shall post notice of the designation on the website of the Metropolitan Police Department and shall post signs in the immediate area of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may extend the duration of the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone to 30 days by issuing a subsequent order extending the duration of the designation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If members of the Metropolitan Police Department discover juveniles in the designated extended juvenile curfew zone during the hours of curfew, the Metropolitan Police Department shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where there:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is not an imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least 2 clearly audible and understandable notices of violation of curfew; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least one clearly audible and understandable notice of violation of curfew;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide juveniles a reasonable and adequate time to disperse; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Capture on body-worn camera each component of the order to return home described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An Advisory Neighborhood Commission, business improvement district, or Main Street organization may petition the Chief of Police to establish an extended juvenile curfew hours zone in an area covered by, or adjacent to the area covered by, such entity. Such petition shall be approved by a formal vote of the members of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission, the members of the board of the business improvement district, or the members of the board of the Main Street organization.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A petition submitted pursuant to this subsection shall include the following information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The proposed boundaries of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The proposed hours of the extended juvenile curfew;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The proposed duration, in days, of the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The reasons why the Advisory Neighborhood Commission, business improvement district, or Main Street organization is requesting the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Such other information as the Chief of Police may require.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Consideration of a petition submitted under this section, and the determination of whether to designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone in response to the petition, shall be at the sole discretion of the Chief of Police.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542" expire="2025-11-07" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 2-1542.02, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3b">§ 3b of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.02" applicability="2025-11-07" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1542.02">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3b">§ 3b of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1542.02">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 5, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3b" display="false">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3b">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-07" eff="2025-11-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3b">§ 3b of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
