<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1542.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 5, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Temporary extensions of juvenile curfew hours.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, by issuance of an administrative order pursuant to <cite path="§1-204.22|(11)">§ 1-204.22(11)</cite>, extend the juvenile curfew hours in the District, or any part of the District, beyond the hours established in <cite path="§2-1542|(1A)|(A)">§ 2-1542(1A)(A)</cite>, <cite path="§2-1542|(1A)|(B)">(B)</cite>, and <cite path="§2-1542|(1A)|(C)">(C)</cite>, if the Mayor determines that such an extension is appropriate to protect public safety or public or private property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An administrative order issued by the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>State the basis for the extension of the juvenile curfew hours;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>State the locations in the District where the extended juvenile curfew hours shall apply or state that the extended juvenile curfew hours shall apply throughout the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>State the days and hours during which the extended juvenile curfew hours shall be in effect; provided, that the extended juvenile curfew hours:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall not begin earlier than 8:00 p.m., nor extend past 6:00 a.m., on any day;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Shall not remain in effect for more than 4 consecutive days, except as provided in subsection (e) of this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Shall not apply to groups of 8 or fewer individuals.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except where emergency circumstances, as determined by the Mayor and described in the administrative order issued under subsection (a) of this section, warrant otherwise, extended juvenile curfew hours imposed under this section shall not take effect until at least 24 hours after the issuance of the administrative order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notice of the issuance of each administrative order issued under this section shall be promptly posted on the main website of the District government and on the website of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may extend the time period during which extended juvenile curfew hours imposed by this section shall remain in effect by issuing subsequent Mayor's orders extending the time period; provided, that each such extension of the time period shall not exceed 30 days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If members of the Metropolitan Police Department discover juveniles in the designated extended juvenile curfew hours zone during the hours of curfew, the Metropolitan Police Department shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where there:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is not an imminent danger of bodily injury of significant damage to property, issue at least 2 clearly audible and understandable notices of violation of curfew; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least one clearly audible and understandable notice of violation of curfew;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide juveniles a reasonable and adequate time to disperse; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Capture on body-worn camera each component of the order to return home described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542" expire="2025-11-07" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 2-1542.01, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3a">§ 3a of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.01" applicability="2025-11-07" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1542.01">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3a">§ 3a of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1542.01">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 5, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3a" display="false">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3a">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-07" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" eff="2025-11-07" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-07" eff="2025-11-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-178" path="§2|(b)|includes|3a">§ 3a of Juvenile Curfew Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-178, Nov. 7, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
