<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>16-1702</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§16-1702(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Recovery of losses at gaming.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who, at any time or sitting, by playing at cards, dice or any other game, or by betting on the sides or hands of persons who play, loses to a person so playing or betting, a sum of money, or other valuable thing, amounting to $25 or more, and pays or delivers the money or thing, or any part thereof, may, within three months after the payment or delivery, sue for and recover the money, goods or other valuable thing, so lost and paid or delivered, or any part thereof, or the full value thereof, by a civil action, from the winner thereof, with costs. If the person who loses the money or other thing, does not, within three months actually and bona fide, and without collusion, sue, and with effect prosecute, therefor, any person may sue for, and recover treble the value of the money, goods, chattels, and other things, with costs of suit, by a civil action against the winner, one-half to the use of the plaintiff, the remainder to the use of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to commercial bingo authorized by <cite path="36|6|I">[subchapter I of Chapter 6 of Title 36]</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>As of May 3, 2019, subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to sports wagering authorized by <cite path="36|6|II">[subchapter II of Chapter 6 of Title 36]</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>As of April 27, 2021, subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to games of skill authorized by <cite path="36|6|III">[subchapter III of Chapter 6 of Title 36]</cite></text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 582, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 16-1702.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 16-1702.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§16-1703">§ 16-1703</cite> and <cite path="§16-1704">§ 16-1704</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2062|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2062|(b)">§ 2062(b) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§2062|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2062|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2062|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2062|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2062|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2062|(b)">§ 2062(b) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
