<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1045</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Establishment of the Office of the Clean City.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Department of Public Works the Office of the Clean City, which shall be headed by a full-time Clean City Coordinator, who shall be appointed by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Clean City Coordinator shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conduct cleanliness assessments on a quarterly basis for the entire District and on an as-needed basis for the District of Columbia National Highway System and provide written reports and GIS maps documenting the outcomes of those assessments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Work in partnership and consultation with the various agencies and offices that have cleanliness and beautification operational responsibility to develop, coordinate and support Clean City program activities and to deliver Clean City services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop, coordinate, and support Clean City program activities with agency divisions that have operational responsibility for maintaining the cleanliness of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Work with agency directors and staff to identify and resolve barriers to effective cooperation among multiple agencies to further the cleanliness of the District in areas, including financial, legal, or procurement services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Assist the Director of the Department of Public Works and the Office of Waste Diversion with innovations in public and household solid-waste container infrastructure and collections;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Advocate for the enforcement of existing laws and municipal regulations that can have a positive impact on the cleanliness and appearance of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Solicit the involvement of ANCs, civic associations, concerned citizens, and businesses in litter-prevention programs and support for the cleaning of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Maintain a website containing information on Clean City activities, education, and community engagement information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Develop and support Clean City Initiative programs to educate and engage District of Columbia Public Schools and Public Charter School students in litter-prevention programs and support for the cleaning of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Formulate and implement a fundraising strategy to solicit corporate and foundation contributions towards Clean City Initiatives, including "Adopt-A-Block" programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Support the coordination of rodent-abatement programs between the Department of Public Works and Department of Health; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Support planning and resource allocation for pet-waste disposal.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to funding, the Clean City Coordinator may issue grants to support public-space cleaning efforts. Such grants shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Preference supporting and expanding the service area of existing Clean Teams funded by the Department of Small and Local Business Development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Prioritize public space cleaning for major arterials, commercial corridors, and mixed-use neighborhoods; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not be used to replace work performed by Department of Public Works staff.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1041.12" expire="2025-11-24" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 8-1045, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§6122|includes|C|127">§ 127 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1045" applicability="2025-11-24" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-1045">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§6122|includes|C|127">§ 127 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1045" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-1045">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="§127" display="false">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="§127">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§6122" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§6122|includes|C|127">§ 127 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§6122" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§6122" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§6122" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§6122" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§6122|includes|C|127">§ 127 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
