<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-1705.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Creditor claim: general power created by powerholder.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "power of appointment created by the powerholder" includes a power of appointment created in a transfer by another person to the extent the powerholder contributed value to the transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Appointive property subject to a general power of appointment created by the powerholder is subject to a claim of a creditor of the powerholder or of the powerholder's estate to the extent provided in §§ <cite path="§28-3101">28-3101</cite> to <cite path="§28-3111">28-3111</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, appointive property subject to a general power of appointment created by the powerholder is not subject to a claim of a creditor of the powerholder or the powerholder's estate to the extent the powerholder irrevocably appointed the property in favor of a person other than the powerholder or the powerholder's estate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, and notwithstanding the presence of a spendthrift provision or whether the claim arose before or after the creation of the power of appointment, appointive property subject to a general power of appointment created by the powerholder is subject to a claim of a creditor of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The powerholder, to the same extent as if the powerholder owned the appointive property, if the power is presently exercisable; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The powerholder's estate, to the extent the estate is insufficient to satisfy the claim and subject to the right of a decedent to direct the source from which liabilities are paid, if the power is exercisable at the powerholder's death.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
