<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-1706.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Application to existing relationships.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, on and after [March 7, 2025], the following rules apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>This chapter applies to a power of appointment created before, on, or after [March 7, 2025];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This chapter applies to a judicial proceeding concerning a power of appointment commenced on or after [March 7, 2025];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>This chapter applies to a judicial proceeding concerning a power of appointment commenced before [March 7, 2025] unless the court finds that application of a particular provision of this chapter would interfere substantially with the effective conduct of the judicial proceeding or prejudice a right of a party, in which case the particular provision of this chapter does not apply and the superseded law applies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A rule of construction or presumption provided in this chapter applies to an instrument executed before [March 7, 2025] unless there is a clear indication of a contrary intent in the terms of the instrument; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (1) through (4) of this subsection, an action done before [March 7, 2025] is not affected by this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a right is acquired, extinguished, or barred on the expiration of a prescribed period that commenced under law of the District of Columbia other than this chapter before [March 7, 2025], the law continues to apply to the right.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
