<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-1909</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Court involvement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On application of an authorized fiduciary a person entitled to notice under <cite path="§19-1907|(c)">§ 19-1907(c)</cite>, a beneficiary, or with respect to a charitable interest the Attorney General or other person that has standing to enforce the charitable interest, the court may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide instructions to the authorized fiduciary regarding whether a proposed exercise of the decanting power is permitted under <cite path="19|19">this chapter</cite> and consistent with the fiduciary duties of the authorized fiduciary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Appoint a special fiduciary and authorize the special fiduciary to determine whether the decanting power should be exercised under <cite path="19|19">this chapter</cite> and to exercise the decanting power;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Approve an exercise of the decanting power;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Determine that a proposed or attempted exercise of the decanting power is ineffective because:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>After applying <cite path="§19-1922">§ 19-1922</cite>, the proposed or attempted exercise does not or did not comply with <cite path="19|19">this chapter</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The proposed or attempted exercise would be or was an abuse of the fiduciary's discretion or a breach of fiduciary duty;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Determine the extent to which <cite path="§19-1922">§ 19-1922</cite> applies to a prior exercise of the decanting power;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Provide instructions to the trustee regarding the application of <cite path="§19-1922">§ 19-1922</cite> to a prior exercise of the decanting power; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Order other relief to carry out the purposes of <cite path="19|19">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On application of an authorized fiduciary, the court may approve:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An increase in the fiduciary's compensation under <cite path="§19-1916">§ 19-1916</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A modification under <cite path="§19-1918">§ 19-1918</cite> of a provision granting a person the right to remove or replace the fiduciary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-266" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-266" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
