<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-1301.12</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Insurable interest of trustee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "settlor" means a person that executes a trust instrument. The term "settlor" includes a person for which a fiduciary or agent is acting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A trustee of a trust has an insurable interest in the life of an individual insured under a life insurance policy that is owned by the trustee of the trust acting in a fiduciary capacity or that designates the trust itself as the owner if, on the date the policy is issued:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The insured is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A settlor of the trust; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An individual in whom a settlor of the trust has, or would have had if living at the time the policy was issued, an insurable interest; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The life insurance proceeds are primarily for the benefit of one or more trust beneficiaries that have:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An insurable interest in the life of the insured; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A substantial interest engendered by love and affection in the continuation of the life of the insured and, if not already included under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, who are:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Related within the third degree or closer, as measured by the civil law system of determining degrees of relation, either by blood or law, to the insured; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Stepchildren of the insured.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-298" type="History">Mar. 21, 2025, D.C. Law 25-298, ยง 2(b)(3), 72 DCR 724</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="ยง2|(b)|(3)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
