<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-1703.05</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Permissible appointment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A powerholder of a general power of appointment that permits appointment to the powerholder or the powerholder's estate may make any appointment, including an appointment in trust or creating a new power of appointment, that the powerholder could make in disposing of the powerholder's own property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A powerholder of a general power of appointment that permits appointment only to the creditors of the powerholder or of the powerholder's estate may appoint only to those creditors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the terms of the instrument creating a power of appointment manifest a contrary intent, the powerholder of a nongeneral power may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make an appointment in any form, including an appointment in trust, in favor of a permissible appointee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Create a general power in a permissible appointee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Create a nongeneral power in any person to appoint to one or more of the permissible appointees of the original nongeneral power; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Create a nongeneral power in a permissible appointee to appoint to one or more persons if the permissible appointees of the new nongeneral power include the permissible appointees of the original nongeneral power.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-265" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
