<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-2102</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="19|21">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Breach of trust" includes a violation by a trust director or trustee of a duty imposed on that director or trustee by the terms of the trust, this chapter, or law of the District other than this chapter pertaining to trusts.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Directed trust" means a trust for which the terms of the trust grant a power of direction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Directed trustee" means a trustee that is subject to a trust director's power of direction.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"District" means the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Power of direction" means a power over a trust granted to a person by the terms of the trust to the extent the power is exercisable while the person is not serving as a trustee. The term "power of direction" includes a power over the investment, management, or distribution of trust property or other matters of trust administration. The term "power of direction" does not include the powers described in <cite path="§19-2105|(b)">§ 19-2105(b)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Settlor" means a person, including a testator, that creates, or contributes property to, a trust. If more than one person creates or contributes property to a trust, each person is a settlor of the portion of the trust property attributable to that person's contribution except to the extent another person has the power to revoke or withdraw that portion.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"State" means a state of the United States, the District, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any other territory or possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Terms of a trust" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the manifestation of the settlor's intent regarding a trust's provisions as:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Expressed in the trust instrument; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Established by other evidence that would be admissible in a judicial proceeding; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The trust's provisions as established, determined, or amended by:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A trustee or trust director in accordance with applicable law;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Court order; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A nonjudicial settlement agreement under <cite path="§19-1301.11">§ 19-1301.11</cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Trust director" means a person that is granted a power of direction by the terms of a trust to the extent the power is exercisable while the person is not serving as a trustee. The person is a trust director whether or not the terms of the trust refer to the person as a trust director and whether or not the person is a beneficiary or settlor of the trust.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Trustee" includes an original, additional, and successor trustee, and a cotrustee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
