<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-2103</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Application; principal place of administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text><cite path="19|21">This chapter</cite> applies to a trust, whenever created, that has its principal place of administration in the District, subject to the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the trust was created before the effective date of this chapter, this chapter applies only to a decision or action occurring on or after the effective date of this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the principal place of administration of the trust is changed to the District on or after the effective date of this chapter, this chapter applies only to a decision or action occurring on or after the date of the change.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Without precluding other means to establish a sufficient connection with the designated jurisdiction in a directed trust, terms of the trust which designate the principal place of administration of the trust are valid and controlling if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A trustee's principal place of business is located in or a trustee is a resident of the designated jurisdiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A trust director's principal place of business is located in or a trust director is a resident of the designated jurisdiction; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All or part of the administration occurs in the designated jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="ยง2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="ยง2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
