<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-2109</num>
  <heading>Duty and liability of directed trustee</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, a directed trustee shall take reasonable action to comply with a trust director's exercise or nonexercise of a power of direction or further power under <cite path="§19-2106|(b)|(1)">§ 19-2106(b)(1)</cite>, and the trustee is not liable for the action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A directed trustee shall not comply with a trust director's exercise or nonexercise of a power of direction or further power under <cite path="§19-2106|(b)|(1)">§ 19-2106(b)(1)</cite> to the extent that by complying the trustee would engage in willful misconduct.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An exercise of a power of direction under which a trust director may release a trustee or another trust director from liability for breach of trust is not effective if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The breach involved the trustee's or other director's willful misconduct;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The release was induced by improper conduct of the trustee or other director in procuring the release; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At the time of the release, the director did not know the material facts relating to the breach.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A directed trustee that has reasonable doubt about its duty under this section may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for instructions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The terms of a trust may impose a duty or liability on a directed trustee in addition to the duties and liabilities under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
