<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-2306</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Disposition of property at death.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>One-half of the property to which <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite> applies belongs to the surviving community-property spouse of a decedent and is not subject to disposition by the decedent at death.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>One-half of the property to which <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite> applies belongs to the decedent and is subject to disposition by the decedent at death.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The property that belongs to the decedent under subsection (b) of this section is not subject to the elective-share right of the surviving community-property spouse.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to property transferred by right of survivorship or under a revocable trust or other nonprobate transfer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section does not limit the right of a surviving community-property spouse to a homestead allowance under <cite path="§19-101.02">§ 19-101.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If at death a decedent purports to transfer to a third person property that, under this section, belongs to the surviving community-property spouse and transfers other property to the surviving community-property spouse, this section does not limit the authority of the court under other law of the District to require that the community-property spouse elect between retaining the property transferred to the community-property spouse or asserting rights under <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
