<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-2309</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Right of heir, devisee, or nonprobate transferee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>An heir, devisee, or nonprobate transferee of a deceased community-property spouse may assert a claim for relief with respect to a right under <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite> in accordance with the following rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In an action asserting a right in or to property, the heir, devisee, or nonprobate transferee must:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Not later than 3 years after the death of the decedent, commence an action against the surviving community-property spouse of the decedent who is in possession of the property; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Not later than 6 months after appointment of the personal representative of the decedent, send a demand in a record to the personal representative; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In an action other than an action under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the heir, devisee, or nonprobate transferee must:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Not later than 6 months after the appointment of the personal representative of the decedent, send a demand in a record to the personal representative; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If a personal representative is not appointed, commence the action not later than 3 years after the death of the decedent.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
