<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-2105</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Exclusions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "power of appointment" means a power that enables a person acting in a nonfiduciary capacity to designate a recipient of an ownership interest in or another power of appointment over trust property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text><cite path="19|21">This chapter</cite> does not apply to a:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Power of appointment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Power to appoint or remove a trustee or trust director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Power of a settlor over a trust to the extent the settlor has a power to revoke the trust;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Power of a beneficiary over a trust to the extent the exercise or nonexercise of the power affects the beneficial interest of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The beneficiary; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Another beneficiary represented by the beneficiary under §§ <cite path="§19-1303.01">19-1303.01</cite> through <cite path="§19-1303.05">19-1303.05</cite> with respect to the exercise or nonexercise of the power; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Power over a trust if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The terms of the trust provide that the power is held in a nonfiduciary capacity; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The power must be held in a nonfiduciary capacity to achieve the settlor's tax objectives under the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and regulations issued thereunder.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the terms of a trust provide otherwise, a power granted to a person to designate a recipient of an ownership interest in or power of appointment over trust property which is exercisable while the person is not serving as a trustee is a power of appointment and not a power of direction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
