<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>19-2302</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Community-property spouse" means an individual in a marriage or other relationship:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Under which community property could be acquired during the existence of the relationship; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>That remains in existence at the time of death of either party to the relationship.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Electronic" means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Jurisdiction" means the United States, a state, a foreign country, or a political subdivision of a foreign country.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Partition" means voluntarily dividing property to which <cite path="19|23">this chapter</cite> otherwise would apply.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Personal representative" includes an executor, administrator, successor personal representative, special administrator, and other person that performs substantially the same function.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Property" means anything that may be the subject of ownership, whether real or personal, tangible or intangible, legal or equitable, or any interest therein.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Reclassify" means to change the characterization or treatment of community property to property owned separately by community-property spouses.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Record" means information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Inscribed on a tangible medium; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Stored in an electronic or other medium and retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Sign" means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic symbol, sound, or process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any other territory or possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. The term "state" includes a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-270" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
