<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-2108</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Duty and liability of trust director.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, with respect to a power of direction or further power under <cite path="§19-2106|(b)|(1)">§ 19-2106(b)(1)</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A trust director has the same fiduciary duty and liability in the exercise or nonexercise of the power:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the power is held individually, as a sole trustee in a like position and under similar circumstances; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the power is held jointly with a trustee or another trust director, as a cotrustee in a like position and under similar circumstances; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The terms of the trust may vary the director's duty or liability to the same extent the terms of the trust could vary the duty or liability of a trustee in a like position and under similar circumstances.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the terms of a trust provide otherwise, if a trust director is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized or permitted by law other than <cite path="19|21">this chapter</cite> to provide health care in the ordinary course of the director's business or practice of a profession, to the extent the director acts in that capacity, the director has no duty or liability under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The terms of a trust may impose a duty or liability on a trust director in addition to the duties and liabilities under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-21" doc="D.C. Law 25-298" eff="2025-03-21" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
