<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.14</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Required reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall provide to the Council and post online the following information associated with the RFK Campus Redevelopment:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All Transaction Documents, within 30 days of execution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All modifications to the Transaction Documents for the duration of the lease, within 30 days of execution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Beginning June 1, 2026, and quarterly thereafter until construction on the Stadium Project is complete, a report regarding the development, design, and construction progress of the Stadium Project, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Financial information, detailing hard and soft costs by initial expected budgets, revised budgets, amount expended in the reporting month, and amount expended to date; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A timeline for completion of the Stadium and any parking facilities;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Beginning October 1, 2026, the Mayor shall transmit, at least quarterly, a report to the Council detailing all First Source compliance information required to be submitted by the Team or the Developer to the Department of Employment Services and all small business enterprise and all certified business enterprise compliance documentation required to be submitted by the Team or the Developer to the Department of Small and Local Business Development, with any personally identifiable information redacted; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Beginning January 1, 2030, a semi-annual report on the activity on the RFK Campus, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Event data, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Number of events hosted at the Stadium, identifying if they are Team Events or non-Team Events;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Number of events hosted on the RFK Campus; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Number of tickets sold and number of attendees per event;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Commercial space data, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Total rentable square feet of commercial space, broken down by type (including apartment/multifamily, office, hotel, and retail);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The vacancy rate of each type of commercial space;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>For each apartment/multifamily space, the number of units with a certificate of occupancy, per building; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>For each hotel, the number of keys and revenue per available room;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The total number of employees of the Team, any Team subsidiary, and the Team's corporate parent whose primary worksite is in the District, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Number of full-time, part-time, and temporary positions; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The state of residence of those employees; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The total number of employees working in the Stadium, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Number of full-time, part-time, and temporary positions;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The state of residence of those employees and, for District employees, ward of residence; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Number of vacant positions.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No sooner than July 1, 2032, the District Department of Transportation, in collaboration with the Team, shall submit a report to the Council analyzing the need for a third parking garage to accommodate traffic associated with the development of the RFK Campus.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, in collaboration with the Team, no later than January 1, 2028, shall produce a report to the Council that includes a site survey, feasibility study, and financial assessment for the inclusion of a new engine and ladder company within the Development Site and as part of the phased construction plans.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The report shall include an estimate of the District funding needed, potential site locations on the RFK Campus, co-location opportunities with planned development sites, and an assessment of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department's needs for the additional apparatus and full staffing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§15" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§15">§ 15 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§15" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§15" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
