<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.31</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor pursuant to subsections (c), (d), and (e) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After all principal and interest on the bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1601.03">§ 10-1601.03</cite>, has been paid, all receipts from the sports facilities fee imposed by <cite path="§47-2762">§ 47-2762</cite> shall be deposited into the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund shall be used:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To pay the debt service, including principal and interest, costs of issuance, and credit enhancements, and any costs of defeasance on bonds issued for RFK campus infrastructure and parking facilities, and to make any other payments related to such bonds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To fund reserves for bonds issued for RFK campus infrastructure and parking facilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For the purposes set forth in and in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any money available in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund in excess of the amounts required to be paid or reserved pursuant to subsection (c)(1) and (2) of this section, as determined by the Chief Financial Officer, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Years 2026 and 2027:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be used to pay the debt service on any ballpark early redemption borrowing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To the extent all debt service on any ballpark early redemption borrowing has been paid, be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the amount of an annual deposit to the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) of this subsection would exceed $20 million, $20 million shall be deposited in the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund, the next $2 million shall be deposited into the Community Reinvestment Fund, established by <cite path="§10-1605.08|(c)">§ 10-1605.08(c)</cite>, and any amount over $22 million shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In Fiscal Year 2030 and each fiscal year thereafter, be transferred to the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund, established in the Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Act of 2025, passed on 1st reading on August 1, 2025 (Engrossed version of Bill 26-288).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the amount of an annual deposit to the RFK Transportation Improvement Fund pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph would exceed $20 million, $20 million shall be deposited in the RFK Transportation Fund and the amount over $20 million shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, may pledge and create a security interest in the funds in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund for the payment of the debt service on any bonds issued for RFK campus infrastructure and parking facilities, any fees and charges incurred in connection therewith, and any payments owing under any document or instrument entered into in connection with such indebtedness in accordance with the provisions of the documents entered into by the District in connection with the issuance of such bonds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsection (d)(3)(B) of this section, the money deposited into the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "RFK campus" means the parcels of land that are the subject of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office of the District of Columbia on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223, together with any public streets within or adjacent to such parcels that may be closed from time to time.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1604.14" expire="2025-11-24" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 10-1605.31, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2052">§ 2052 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.31" applicability="2025-11-24" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-1605.31">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2052">§ 2052 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.31" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-1605.31">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2052" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2052">§ 2052 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§2052" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2052" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§2052" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2052" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§2052">§ 2052 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
