<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.03</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Applicability of certain laws to Transaction Documents, Development Site, easements over the RFK Campus, and the sale of Stadium Seat Rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Neither <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite>, nor <cite path="2|2A">Chapter 2A of Title 2</cite>, shall apply to the Transaction Documents nor any other agreement the Mayor may enter into under the Term Sheet; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <cite path="§10-1605.05">§ 10-1605.05</cite> have been met.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to purport to waive <cite path="§1-204.51">§ 1-204.51</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="10|8|I">subchapter I of Chapter 8 of this title</cite>, the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Dispose of the Development Site by lease pursuant to the terms of the Term Sheet; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <cite path="§10-1605.05">§ 10-1605.05</cite> have been met;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sell Stadium Seat Rights to the Developer pursuant to the terms of the Term Sheet; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Grant easements over the RFK Campus to such persons as the Mayor determines appropriate in furtherance of the redevelopment of the RFK Campus; provided, that the preconditions for the issuance of bonds and the expenditure of bond proceeds set forth in <cite path="§10-1605.05">§ 10-1605.05</cite> have been met.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text><cite path="§8-651.04a">§ 8-651.04a</cite>, shall not apply to the Development Site; provided, that a fee calculated at the rate applicable for special trees pursuant to <cite path="§8-651.04|(b)|(3)">§ 8-651.04(b)(3)</cite>, shall be paid for each Heritage Tree removed from the Development Site;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The waiver of <cite path="§8-651.04a">§ 8-651.04a</cite> set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to the Anacostia Commons riparian area.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The utility and site preparation work related to the Stadium Project and construction of the Stadium Project shall not be subject to <cite path="§6-1108.02">§ 6-1108.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Developer shall provide affordable housing for the Development Site in an amount that equals or exceeds 30% of the residential units, with 1/2 of the affordable units set aside for households earning equal to or less than 60% of the median family income ("MFI") and 1/2 of the affordable units set aside for households earning equal to or less than 30% of the MFI ("Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement shall be calculated based on the total number of developed units rather than on a per building basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Inclusionary zoning requirements shall not be applicable to the Development Site.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To provide flexibility to deliver all housing types in an expedited and efficient manner, all other details (such as duration of affordability, lottery, and the certification process for the affordable dwelling units) regarding the implementation of the Affordable Dwelling Unit Requirement shall be as set forth in the Transaction Documents.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§4" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§4">§ 4 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§4" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
