<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.08</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Community benefits and Community Reinvestment Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Community Benefits Agreement ("CBA") required pursuant to <cite path="§10-1605.05|(a)|(2)">§ 10-1605.05(a)(2)</cite> shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Require the Team, or an affiliate thereof, to invest no less than $50 million over 30 years in community benefits for the District in accordance with its negotiated terms;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be executed by the Mayor, the Chairman of the Council, and the Team, or their designees, after all 3 signatories to the CBA, or their designees, meet together no fewer than 3 times to negotiate its terms; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Include initiatives that promote the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Local economic development and job creation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Community access and activation of the RFK Campus;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Youth education, including youth sports team support, workforce development, and housing stability;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Health equity and environmental sustainability; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Public safety and cultural heritage at and surrounding the RFK Campus in coordination with District agencies and community stakeholders.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A Community Benefits Oversight Committee ("CBOC") shall monitor the implementation of the CBA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The CBOC shall consist of 9 members, who shall be appointed within one month of the execution of the CBA, as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Councilmember that represents the Ward in which the Stadium is located shall appoint 3 members;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each Councilmember that represents a Ward contiguous to the Ward in which the Stadium is located shall appoint one member;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Chairman of the Council shall appoint one member; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall appoint 2 members.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The CBOC shall be subject to the terms established in the CBA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The CBOC shall request, review, and publish timely progress reports, provided by the Team, in accordance with the reporting requirements established in the CBA.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund, the Community Reinvestment Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor, DMPED, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor or designated by law, with oversight by the CBOC, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Community Reinvestment Fund shall consist of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any monetary donations from the Team to the District, as negotiated in the CBA;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Excess RFK Campus Infrastructure Funds, up to $2 million annually, pursuant to section 2052(d)(2) of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any money deposited in the Community Reinvestment Fund pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection shall be used to finance the community benefits outlined in the CBA and this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Funds deposited in the Community Reinvestment Fund pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection shall be disbursed to census tracts within Wards 5, 6, 7, and 8 identified as a low-income community, as that term is defined in 26 U.S.C. § 45D(e), with a priority given to communities most directly impacted by Stadium operations and redevelopment. These funds shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Displacement prevention, including rental assistance, utility assistance, legal representation in eviction proceedings, property tax relief for long-term homeowners, and homebuyer assistance;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Blight revitalization and housing stabilization, including grants or low-interest loans for the rehabilitation of vacant or blighted properties and stabilization of at-risk housing stock;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Small business and community wealth programs, including micro-grants for minority owned small business, workforce training programs tied to stadium operations, and community based development initiatives; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Public health programs, including grants to fund neighborhood beautification projects and other emerging health needs.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the Community Reinvestment Fund but not expended in a given fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Community Reinvestment Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitations.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§9" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§9">§ 9 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§9" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§9" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
