<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of §§ <cite path="§10-1605.01">10-1605.01</cite> through <cite path="§10-1605.14">10-1605.14</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Authorized Delegate" means the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, the Chief Financial Officer, the Treasurer, or any officer or employee of the executive office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated any of the Mayor's functions under <cite path="10|16|V|A">this part</cite> pursuant to <cite path="§1-204.22|(6)">§ 1-204.22(6)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Bonds" means District revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including bonds, notes, and other obligations) in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to <cite path="§1-204.90">§ 1-204.90</cite> and <cite path="10|16|V|A">this part</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Certified business enterprise" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-218.02|(1D)">§ 2-218.02(1D)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Chief Financial Officer" means the Chief Financial Officer established by <cite path="§1-204.24a|(a)">§ 1-204.24a(a)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Closing Documents" means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Commercial Development" shall have the same meaning as provided in the Term Sheet.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Declaration of Covenants" means the Declaration of Covenants Regarding the Transfer of Jurisdiction of the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium Campus (Reservation 343F), dated as of January 14, 2025, and recorded in the land records of the District of Columbia on February 4, 2025, as Instrument No. 2025012660.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Debt Service" means principal, premium, if any, and interest on the Bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Developer" means Pro-Football LLC, or affiliates or designees of Pro-Football LLC approved by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Development and Financing Agreement" means the agreement governing the terms and conditions of the District's funding for the RFK Campus and the Developer's obligation to construct the Stadium Project.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Development Site" means the portions of the RFK Campus that are the subject of the Term Sheet.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"District Event" means any Stadium use for a District-sponsored, non-commercial public or community event, such as a graduation, high school football game, or similar use, even if such event charges fees for attendance; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any other event agreed to be a District event jointly by the Team and the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Financing Documents" means the documents that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effectuated through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Home Rule Act" means <cite path="1|2">Chapter 2 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Net Parking Revenues" means all parking revenues collected at the Parking Facilities less 15% for operating costs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"Parking Facilities" means the parking facilities constructed pursuant to the Development and Financing Agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>"Personal Seat License" means a license, location right, or other similar instrument for seats in the Stadium issued to a person for the right to purchase season tickets to games and tickets to other events at the Stadium.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>"RFK Campus" means the parcels of land that are the subject of the Transfer of Jurisdiction Plat recorded in the Surveyor's Office of the District of Columbia on February 5, 2025, on page 13 of subdivision book 223, together with any public streets within or adjacent to such parcels that may be closed from time to time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>"RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund" means the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund established by section 2052 of the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Act of 2025, enacted on September 4, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-148; 72 DCR 9825).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>"RFK Campus Infrastructure Project" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred in the development, design, and construction of the horizontal improvements and eligible capital costs as defined in the Term Sheet;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The funding of any required deposit to a debt service reserve fund or capitalized interest for the Bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1605.11|(a)">§ 10-1605.11(a)</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The payment of certain costs of issuance of the Bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1605.11|(a)">§ 10-1605.11(a)</cite>, such as fees and premiums for any bond issuance or credit enhancement.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>"RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund" means the RFK Campus Parking Facilities Fund established by <cite path="§10-1605.09">§ 10-1605.09</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>"RFK Campus Parking Facilities Project" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of costs incurred in the development, design, and construction of the Parking Facilities and horizontal improvements and eligible capital costs as defined in the Term Sheet;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The funding of any required deposit to a debt service reserve fund or capitalized interest for the Bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1605.11|(b)">§ 10-1605.11(b)</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The payment of certain costs of issuance of the Bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1605.11|(b)">§ 10-1605.11(b)</cite>, such as fees and premiums for any bond issuance or credit enhancement.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>"Small business enterprise" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-218.02|(16)">§ 2-218.02(16)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(24)</num>
      <text>"Sportsplex" means a public sports and recreation facility to be developed on the Development Site.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(25)</num>
      <text>"Stadium" means the stadium to be constructed by the Developer and owned by the District on a portion of the Development Site, as described in the Term Sheet.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(26)</num>
      <text>"Stadium Event Day" means the Stadium Event Day Interval on each day on which any Team Event is scheduled to be held at all or any part of the Stadium (including periods after midnight for any such Team Event that extends past that hour).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(27)</num>
      <text>"Stadium Event Day Interval" means the period beginning 10 hours before the scheduled start time for commencement of any Team Event and terminating 4 hours following the conclusion of such Team Event.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(28)</num>
      <text>"Stadium Maintenance Fund" means the special fund established by <cite path="§10-1605.10">§ 10-1605.10</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(29)</num>
      <text>"Stadium Project" means the development on a portion of the Development Site to include the construction of the Stadium, the Parking Facilities, administrative offices, and other ancillary improvements by the Developer, as described in the Term Sheet.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(30)</num>
      <text>"Stadium Seat Right" means the right to sell, license, or otherwise transfer certain rights to use and occupy seats in the Stadium, including a Personal Seat License.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(31)</num>
      <text>"Team" means the professional football franchise that is a member club of the National Football League ("NFL") known as the Washington Commanders, or a successor member club.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(32)</num>
      <text>"Team Event" means any Team home game, any NFL sponsored event, and any other event at the Stadium that is not a District Event and that is attended by 5,000 or more visitors, including any unticketed such event.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(33)</num>
      <text>"Term Sheet" means the Term Sheet for the Redevelopment of a Portion of the RFK Stadium Campus between the District and Pro-Football LLC, dated April 28, 2025, that memorializes the terms of the disposition and development of the Development Site.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(34)</num>
      <text>"Transaction Document" means any document entered into under the Term Sheet that implements the terms of the disposition and development of the Development Site, including the Development and Financing Agreement and any leases entered into by the parties.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(35)</num>
      <text>"Transportation Improvement Fund" means the special fund established by <cite path="§50-921.29">§ 50-921.29</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§2">§ 2 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
