<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.10</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Stadium Maintenance Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Stadium Maintenance Fund, which shall be administered by the Mayor, or any District instrumentality or authority designated by the Mayor, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Excess Stadium Revenue Funds, as provided in <cite path="§10-1605.09|(d)">§ 10-1605.09(d)</cite>, shall be deposited into the Stadium Maintenance Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be used to pay maintenance, repair, and capital expenses of the Stadium. Any maintenance, repair, and capital expenses in excess of available funds in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be the responsibility of the Developer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Stadium Maintenance Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council an annual report of the funds deposited in and expended from the Stadium Maintenance Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§11" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-21" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§11">§ 11 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 72 DCR 10584)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§11" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-21" doc="D.C. Law 26-54" eff="2025-11-21" path="§11" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
