<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-562.02</num>
  <heading>Annual Enforcement Report.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On or before January 1, 2023, and January 1 of every year thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Council an annual report detailing the enforcement activities of the Department in the prior fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report required under subsection (a) of this section shall assess the Department's progress against the Strategic Enforcement Plan required under <cite path="§10-562.01">§ 10-562.01</cite> and identify any changes to operations necessary to implement the Strategic Enforcement Plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The report required under subsection (a) of this section shall also include the following data for the prior fiscal year:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Complaint data, detailing the number, type, method, determination of validity, and resolution of complaints received by the Department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Violation data, detailing the violations identified and cited in the prior fiscal year and their status as abated or unresolved as of the date of the report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fine collection data, detailing the dollar value of the fines assessed, dollar value of the fines assessed versus the fines collected, violations for which the fines were issued, and identifying any reduction in fine amount due to an action by an administrative judge to reduce the assessed fine, adverse judgment at an administrative hearing, administrative settlement or dismissal by the Department, or other means resulting in a collection of less than the levied amount, and any fines not yet collected as of the date of the report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Abatement efficacy, detailing the number and nature of abatement orders, the number of days taken to abate each order, the number of extensions granted by type of abatement order, the justification for each extension, and the location of each abatement order, and its status as abated or unresolved as of the date of the report;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Enforcement escalation data, detailing the number of violations referred to the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, the aggregate dollar amount assessed, and a description of the matters referred; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Collections escalation data, detailing the number of violations referred to the Central Collections Unit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the January 1, 2026 annual enforcement plan required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the following information shall be included:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A description of predictive statistical models that could be used to identify properties at risk of becoming vacant or blighted, as well as the data sources and information technology infrastructure necessary to effectively implement these models;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A detailed description of proactive measures utilized by other jurisdictions in the United States to enforce vacant and blighted property registration ordinances; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An analysis and determination of the feasibility of utilizing proactive measures to enforce the District's laws regarding registration and maintenance of vacant and blighted buildings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the January 1, 2027 annual enforcement plan required pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and for the annual enforcement plans issued every 3 years thereafter, the Director shall include a vacant and blighted property rehabilitation strategic plan. In developing the strategic plan, the Director shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Analyze the extent and nature of interagency collaboration among District agencies with respect to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Enforcing legal requirements related to vacant and blighted buildings in the District; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Incentivizing the successful redevelopment or rehabilitation of vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Review the use and effectiveness of existing incentives in the District that support the redevelopment or rehabilitation of vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Review best practices for preventing vacancy and blight and best practices for redeveloping or rehabilitating vacant and blighted buildings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Develop and refine performance metrics that measure the effectiveness of the District's programs, interventions, and incentives regarding vacant and blighted properties; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Consult with stakeholders, including the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Organizations with significant experience redeveloping or rehabilitating vacant or blighted buildings; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Organizations or individuals with policy or research expertise on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Implementing strategic code enforcement programs;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Housing development incentives; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Developing performance measures.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-562.02" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-562.02">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="">D.C. Law 23-269</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 23-269</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§202">§ 202 of D.C. Law 23-269</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-04-05" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" eff="2021-04-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-05" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" eff="2021-04-05" path="§202" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§202" codified:display="Note" app="2021-04-05" eff="2021-04-05">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="">D.C. Law 23-269</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 23-269</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§202">§ 202 of D.C. Law 23-269</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-45" path="§7207" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2021-11-13" eff="2021-11-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 24-45" path="§7207">Section 7276 of D.C. Law 24-45</cite> repealed the applicability provision of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-269" path="§601">section 601 of D.C. Law 23-269</cite> that impacted this section.  Therefore the creation of this section by Law 23-269 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-11-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-45" eff="2021-11-13" path="§7207" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2024-03-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-141" eff="2024-03-23" path="§9" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 25-141" eff="2024-03-23" path="§8" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 25-141" path="§8" codified:display="Note" app="2024-03-23" eff="2024-03-23">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-141" path="">D.C. Law 25-141</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-141" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 25-141</cite> provided that the amendment to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-141" path="§8">§ 8 of D.C. Law 25-141</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-03-23" doc="D.C. Law 25-141" eff="2024-03-23" path="§8" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-41" eff="2025-10-01" path="§201" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
