<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-417</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 8, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established by the Council an Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force ("Task Force"), which shall have, as of the effective date of the Early Childhood Educator Pay Scales Emergency Amendment Act of 2025, passed on emergency basis on October 21, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-433) ("ECE Pay Scales Amendment Act"), the same members as the Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force established pursuant to the Early Childhood Educator Equitable Compensation Task Force Act of 2021, effective November 13, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-45, D.C. Official Code § 38-2241 <em>et seq</em>.), until their successors are appointed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Task Force shall be composed of the Chairman of the Council, or his or her designee, the State Superintendent of Education, or his or her designee, and 12 District residents, appointed by the Chairman, representing the following entities or groups:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Families whose children are receiving or have received early childhood education or childcare services from early childhood development facilities in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Community-based organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Early childhood education associations, advocacy or research organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Operators of child development facilities who participate in the childcare subsidy programs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Operators of child development facilities who do not currently participate in the childcare subsidy program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Operators of home-based child development facilities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Employees of child development facilities; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>An individual with an expertise in economics or policy, who has an understanding of the District's early childhood development and education sector.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>[(2)]</num>
      <text>At least 2 members of the Task Force shall be employees of child development facilities, one of whom shall be a participant in the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>[(3)]</num>
      <text>The Chairman, or his or her designee, shall serve as the Chairperson of the Task Force.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Following the effective date of the ECE Pay Scales Amendment Act, the Task Force shall convene:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least every 3rd calendar year starting in 2027; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When deemed necessary by the Chairman of the Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 60 days after the Department publishes the report required pursuant to section 11b(c), the Task Force shall meet and submit a response to the Council that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reviews the Department's report, the recommended salary scales, the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program funding formula, and the state of the early childhood education workforce; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Makes recommendations to improve systemic supports.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Should a vacancy occur on the Task Force after the effective date of the ECE Pay Scales Amendment Act, the Chairman, in consultation with the State Superintendent of Education, shall appoint an individual to fill the vacancy whose qualifications and experience are comparable to those of the individual who vacated the role, and whose appointment maintains the composition requirements set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-416" expire="2025-11-10" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 4-417, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(e)|includes|15c">§ 15c of Early Childhood Educator Pay Scales Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-196, Nov. 10, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-417" applicability="2025-11-10" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-417">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(e)|includes|15c">§ 15c of Early Childhood Educator Pay Scales Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-196, Nov. 10, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-417" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-417">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 8, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16" type="History" path="§15c" display="false">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 15c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16" type="History" path="§15c">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 15c</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-10" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" eff="2025-11-10" path="§2|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-10" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" eff="2025-11-10" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-10" eff="2025-11-10">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(e)|includes|15c">§ 15c of Early Childhood Educator Pay Scales Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-196, Nov. 10, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
