<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-410.04</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 8, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§4-410.04(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund ("Fund"), which shall be a continuation of the fund <cite path="§1-325.431">§ 1-325.431</cite>, and administered by the Department in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following funds shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2022, $53,920,878 in local funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2023, $72,889,092 in local funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2024, $69,508,332 in local funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2025, $70,000,000 in local funds; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2026, $72,126,902 in local funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Support the implementation of the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to appropriations, reduce health insurance premiums paid by child development facilities, or employees of child development facilities eligible to receive the minimum salaries listed in <cite path="§4-410.02">§ 4-410.02</cite>, pursuant to an agreement with the District of Columbia Health Benefit Exchange; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Pay the Department administrative costs related to implementing the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Program, which may include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Personnel and associated non-personnel costs;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Grantee or contractor costs related to distributing Fund monies; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Costs related to providing technical assistance to child development facilities.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Administrative costs authorized to be paid pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not exceed 5% of the annual amount deposited in the Fund.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise prohibited by federal law, lump-sum payments an individual receives from the Fund shall not be counted as income or assets:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of determining eligibility or calculating benefits under <cite path="4|2">Chapter 2 of this title</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of determining eligibility or calculating benefits for the following benefit programs:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>D.C. HealthCare Alliance, referenced in <cite path="§7-771.07|(2)">§ 7-771.07(2)</cite>, or any subsequent program established to provide public health insurance coverage to residents ineligible for Medicaid;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Educational scholarships the District administers with local funds;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Home Purchase Assistance Program, referenced in <cite path="§42-2602.01">§ 42-2602.01</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Housing subsidy vouchers issued through the Rent Supplement Program, established by <cite path="§6-226">§ 6-226</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Grandparent Caregiver Program established by <cite path="§4-251.02">§ 4-251.02</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Close Relative Caregiver Program, established by <cite path="§4-251.22">§ 4-251.22</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Other District government benefit programs administered with local funds, including Strong Families, Strong Futures.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16" type="History" path="§11d">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 11d</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-16" type="History" path="§11d" display="false">Sept. 19, 1979, D.C. Law 3-16, § 11d</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-03-19" doc="D.C. Law 23-68" eff="2020-03-19" path="§5" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-68" path="§5" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2020-03-19">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-68" path="§5">§ 5 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Clarification Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Law 23-68, Mar. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 743)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-68" eff="2020-03-19" path="§5" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="§7022|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-10" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" eff="2025-11-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-10" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" eff="2025-11-10" path="§2|(c)" prefix="revived" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-10" eff="2025-11-10">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-196" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Early Childhood Educator Pay Scales Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-196, Nov. 10, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
