<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-754.36a-1</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Discontinuation of services under a Rapid Re-Housing program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each client shall be exited from a Rapid Re-Housing program at the end of the time limit for services under the program. The time limit for assistance under the program shall be established by the Mayor by rule, but shall not be shorter than 12 months.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may extend a client's time limit for services in a Rapid Re-Housing program beyond the time limit established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section and procedures established by the Mayor by rule. If the Mayor extends a client's time limit pursuant to this subsection, the client shall be exited from the Rapid Re-Housing program at the end of the extended time limit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The provision for continuation of services under <cite path="§4-754.36b|(c)|(1)">§ 4-754.36b(c)(1)</cite> shall not apply to a client who receives a notice of program exit from a Rapid Re-Housing program pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of this section on or after September 3, 2025.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A client who received a notice of program exit from a Rapid Re-Housing program before September 3, 2025, when the exit was due to the end of a time limit for services to the client under the program, shall be exited from the Rapid Re-Housing program when the client's time in the program reaches 24 months or on September 30, 2025, whichever date is later.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A program exit provided for in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall occur regardless of the pendency of an administrative review, fair hearing, or other appeal in which the client seeks to remain in the Rapid Re-Housing program beyond the client's time limit for services and notwithstanding any statutory provision requiring the continuation of services that existed on or before the date the client received the notice of program exit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A determination of whether to consider a request to extend a client's time limit for services in a Rapid Re-Housing program need not be made on an individualized basis, and any determination of whether to consider or grant a request to extend a client's time limit for services on the basis of the unavailability of funds shall be in the sole and absolute discretion of the Director of the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall apply as of November 27, 2024.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36a" expire="2025-11-24" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 4-754.36a-1, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5102|(b)|includes|22a-1">§ 22a-1 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36a-1" applicability="2025-11-24" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-754.36a-1">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5102|(b)|includes|22a-1">§ 22a-1 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-754.36a-1" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-754.36a-1">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§22a-1" display="false">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 22a-1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§22a-1">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 22a-1</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5102|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§5102|(b)|includes|22a-1">§ 22a-1 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§5102|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5102|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§5102|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5102|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§5102|(b)|includes|22a-1">§ 22a-1 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
