<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2762</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§47-2762(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Sports facilities fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the fiscal year beginning October 1, 2004, and each fiscal year thereafter, each feepayer shall remit, on or before June 15 of each year, a sports facilities fee that shall be based upon the annual District gross receipts of the feepayer for the feepayer's preceding tax year and computed according to the fee schedule provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A feepayer that is exempt from taxation pursuant to <cite path="§47-1802.01">§ 47-1802.01</cite> shall not be subject to the sports facilities fee unless, as provided in <cite path="§47-1802.01">§ 47-1802.01</cite>, the feepayer has unrelated business income subject to tax under section 511 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 169; 26 U.S.C. § 511). If the feepayer exempt from taxation has unrelated business income, the feepayer shall remit the sports facilities fee based upon the feepayer’s annual District gross receipts that were associated with the feepayer’s unrelated business income for the feepayer’s preceding fiscal year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The amount of the sports facilities fee shall be computed according to the following schedule:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each feepayer with annual District gross receipts of $5,000,000 to $8,000,000 shall pay $5,500;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each feepayer with annual District gross receipts of $8,000,001 to $12,000,000 shall pay $10,800;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each feepayer with annual District gross receipts of $12,000,001 to $16,000,000 shall pay $14,000; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Each feepayer with annual District gross receipts of greater than $16,000,001 shall pay $16,500.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On or before December 1 of each year, the Chief Financial Officer shall certify to the Council the amount of revenue received by the District from imposition of the sports facilities fee during the immediately preceding fiscal year and provide an estimate of the amount of revenue expected to be received from the sports facilities fee in the then current fiscal year. If the amount estimated to be collected is less than annual debt service on the bonds plus any amount necessary to replenish any reserve funds in accordance with the financing documents and to avoid any projected shortfall in debt service on the bonds, the Chief Financial Officer shall compute the amount of the sports facilities fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section needed to provide estimated revenue in the current fiscal year equal to annual debt service on the bonds plus any amount necessary to replenish any reserve funds in accordance with the financing documents and to avoid any projected shortfall in debt service on the bonds, by applying the same percentage increase to each amount of the then-current sports facilities fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section. The Chief Financial Officer shall notify the Council, the Mayor, and the feepayers of the new schedule and, upon such notice, the amount of the sports facilities fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall be increased as of October 1 of the current fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The revenues received by the District from the sports facilities fee imposed by this section shall be deposited into the Ballpark Revenue Fund; except, that after all principal and interest on the bonds issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1601.03">[§ 10-1601.03]</cite>, has been paid, the revenues received by the District from the sports facilities fee imposed by this section shall be deposited in the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§2052">section 2052 of  the RFK Campus Infrastructure Fund Establishment Emergency Act of 2025, effective September 3, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146; 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except in the case of street vendors described in <cite path="§47-2002.01">§ 47-2002.01</cite>, the Chief Financial Officer may require taxpayers subject to the sales taxes and fees imposed by §§ <cite path="§47-2002.05">47-2002.05</cite> and <cite path="§47-2762">47-2762</cite> and all sales taxes described in [<cite path="§2-1217.12">§ 2-1217.12</cite>], to make payments of those taxes electronically.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer or his delegate shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-320" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-320, § 110(f), 52 DCR 1757</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91" type="History">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 204, 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-149" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-149, § 2(b), 59 DCR 5129</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 136 of Pub. L. 109-115, Nov. 30, 2005, 119 Stat. 2522, provided: “Notwithstanding section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, amendments to the Ballpark Technical Amendments Act of 2005 shall take effect on the date of the enactment by the District of Columbia [Nov. 30, 2005].”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-149">D.C. Law 19-149</cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “The” for “Except in the case of street vendors described in <cite path="§47-2002.01">§ 47-2002.01</cite>, the”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite> rewrote subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) On or before December 1 of each year, the Chief Financial Officer shall certify to the Council the amount of revenue received by the District from imposition of the ballpark fee during the immediately preceding fiscal year and provide an estimate of the amount of revenue expected to be received from the ballpark fee in the then current fiscal year. If the amount estimated to be collected is less than $26 million, for the allocation of monies for payments of the bonds, as provided by <cite path="§10-1601.03|(b)">§ 10-1601.03(b)</cite>, the Chief Financial Officer shall compute the amount of the ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section needed to provide estimated revenue in the next fiscal year equal to $26 million by applying the same percentage increase to each amount of the then-current ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section. The Chief Financial Officer shall notify the Council, the Mayor, and the taxpayers of the new schedule and, upon such notice, the amount of the ballpark fee under the schedule set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall be increased as of October 1 of the following year.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§10-1601.06">§ 10-1601.06</cite> and <cite path="§47-2763">§ 47-2763</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7042|(b)|(3)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7042|(b)|(3)">§ 7042(b)(3) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§7042|(b)|(3)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(B)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(B)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(D)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(D)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7042|(b)|(3)|(E)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7042|(b)|(3)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7042|(b)|(3)">§ 7042(b)(3) of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
