<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-2851.01</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="47|28|I-A">[this subchapter]</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Basic business license" means the single document designed for public display issued by the Department that certifies a business to operate from a location in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Beauty and grooming services" means personal services related to hairstyling, nail care, and cosmetics, including haircuts, color treatments, manicures, pedicures, chemical exfoliation, waxing, makeup application, electrolysis hair removal, and other similar services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Business" means a trade, profession, or activity that provides, or holds itself out to provide, goods or services to the general public or to a portion of the general public for hire or compensation in the District of Columbia. The term "business" does not include the activities of a government entity or employment for wages or salary.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Business License Center" means the business registration and licensing center established by this subchapter and located in and under the administrative control of the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Charitable services" means any service whose actual or purported purpose is benevolent, philanthropic, patriotic, educational (except religious education), scientific, environmental conservation, civic, or otherwise eleemosynary.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Contractor and construction services" means any services that involve the planning, acquiring, building, equipping, altering, repairing, improving, or demolishing of any structure or appurtenance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Cottage food products" means any non-potentially hazardous food, as specified in regulations adopted by the Department of Health, that is sold to consumers, including through direct, retail, and online sales, within the District of Columbia in accordance with <cite path="§7-742.02">§ 7-742.02</cite> and regulations adopted by the Department of Health.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection or any successor agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Director" means the Director of the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection or any successor agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Entertainment services" means a performance, recreational activity, spectacle, show, or similar event or service, including events or services occurring at amusement parks, bowling alleys, skating rinks, and theaters.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Environmental services" means any service meant to store, transport, or distribute fuels or solvents, remediate pests or environmental contaminants, and store, transport, or collect solid waste.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Food services" means any handling of food or food products regulated under title 25 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations ("DCMR").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"General sales and services" means any services that are not covered by other business license categories in <cite path="47|28|I-A">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Health services" means the operation of a swimming pool regulated under title 25C of the DCMR or a pet shop regulated under title 25J of the DCMR.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Housing and lodging services" means the provision of short-term or long-term housing or lodging for residents and visitors in the District, including one-family rentals, two-family rentals, apartments, short-term rentals, hotels, bed and breakfasts, and other similar services.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"License" means the whole or part of any agency permit, license, certificate, approval, registration, charter, or any form or permission required by law, including agency rule, to engage in any activity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>"Person" means an individual, sole proprietorship, partnership, association, cooperative, corporation, nonprofit organization, and any other organization required to obtain one or more licenses from the District or any of its agencies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>"Public safety services" means any service whose primary purpose is to protect the safety, health, or property of residents of the District, including furnishing security systems, alarms, and personnel.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>"Regulation" means any licensing or other governmental or statutory requirement pertaining to business or professional activities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>"Regulatory agency" means any District agency, board, commission, or division that regulates one or more professions, occupations, industries, businesses, or activities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>"Vehicular services" means the repair, servicing, alteration, restoration, towing, painting, cleaning, finishing, or parking of automobiles, trucks, recreational vehicles, boats and other vehicles, boats and other vehicles as a primary use, which may include the incidental wholesale and retail sale of vehicle parts as an accessory use.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 101(b), 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2002(b), (c), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 2(c), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 73(l)(5), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4 of Law 15-38 provided: “Within 16 months of the effective date of this act, the Mayor shall provide the Council with a 12-month report on the effect of this act on the regulatory, economic development, and consumer protection operations of the District of Columbia, with recommendations for modification to the District of Columbia’s regulatory framework, as warranted.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-45, March 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2812).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-415, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7382).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-535, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11645).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Religious Organization Exemption Amendment Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-216">D.C. Law 14-216</cite>, March 25, 2002, law notification  50 DCR 2729).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in par. (1B), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, added new par. (1); added par. (1A); redesignated existing par. (1)(A) as par. (1B)(A); in redesignated par. (1B)(A), substituted “in the District of Columbia.” for “, and which pays, or is subject to the payment of, taxes on earnings, or fees in lieu of taxes, to the District of Columbia, or which qualifies for tax-exempt status under District law.”; repealed pars. (6) and (7); in par. 8, deleted “to register with the District to do business in the District and”; and, in par. (12), substituted “basic” for “master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2851.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§22-4510">§ 22-4510</cite>, <cite path="§37-131.02">§ 37-131.02</cite>, and <cite path="§47-2855.01">§ 47-2855.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-05" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" eff="2021-04-05" path="§501|(bb)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-333" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(c)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(c)|(1)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-03-22">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="">D.C. Law 24-333</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(c)|(1)">§ 5(c)(1) of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(c)|(1)" type="Applicability" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-03-22"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286">Section 7286 of D.C. Law 25-217</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(c)|(1)">Section 5(c)(1) of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> shall apply as of October 1, 2025.  Therefore those amendments have been implemented.
         </annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-09-18"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286">Section 7286 of D.C. Law 25-217</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§9">section 9 of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> making the amendment of this section by section 5(c)(1) of D.C. Law 24-333 applicable as of October 1, 2025.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§7286" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
