<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-2853.76</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Board" means the Board of Barber and Cosmetology.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Body art" or "body art procedure" means the process of physically modifying the body for cosmetic or other non-medical purposes, including tattooing, body piercing, and fixing indelible marks or figures on the skin through scarification, branding, tongue bifurcation, and tissue removal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Body artist" means an individual who is licensed under this chapter to perform body art procedures.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Body art establishment" means any structure or venue, whether temporary or permanent, where body art procedures are performed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Body piercing" means the perforation of any human body part followed by the insertion of an object, such as jewelry, for cosmetic or other non-medical purposes by using any of the following instruments, methods, or processes: stud and clasp, captive ball, soft tissue, cartilage, surface, surface-to-surface, microdermal implantation or dermal anchoring, subdermal implantation, and transdermal implantation. The term "body piercing" does not include nail piercing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Branding" means the process of applying extreme heat with a pen-like instrument to create an image or pattern.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Cleansing product" means any material used to apply cleansing agents to the skin, such as cotton balls, tissue or paper products, paper or plastic cups, towels, gauze, or sanitary coverings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Operator" means a person who owns, controls, or operates a body art establishment, whether or not the person actually performs body art procedures.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Sanitization" means the reduction of the population of microorganisms to safe levels, as determined by the Department of Health, by a product registered with the Environmental Protection Agency ("EPA") or by chemical germicides that are registered with the EPA as hospital disinfectants.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Scarification" means the placing of an indelible mark on the skin by the process of cutting or abrading the skin to bring about permanent scarring.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Sharps" means any object, sterile or contaminated, that may penetrate the skin or mucosa, including pre-sterilized single needles, scalpel blades, and razor blades.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Single-use" means products or items intended for one-time use that are disposed of after use on a client.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Sterilization" means the process of destruction of all forms of life by physical or chemical means.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Tattoo" means the placing of pigment into the skin dermis for cosmetic or other non-medical purposes, including the process of micro-pigmentation or cosmetic tattooing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Tissue removal" means placing an indelible mark or figure on the skin through the removal of a portion of the dermis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"Tongue bifurcation" means the cutting of the tongue from tip to part of the way toward the base, forking at the end.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 24-333" eff="2023-03-22" path="§5|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(d)|(2)" codified:display="Note" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-03-22">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="">D.C. Law 24-333</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(d)|(2)">§ 5(d)(2) of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(d)|(2)" type="Applicability" app="2023-03-22" eff="2023-03-22"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286">Section 7286 of D.C. Law 25-217</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§5|(d)|(2)">Section 5(d)(2) of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> shall apply as of October 1, 2025.  Therefore those amendments have been implemented.
         </annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2024-09-18" eff="2024-09-18"><cite doc="D.C. Law 25-217" path="§7286">Section 7286 of D.C. Law 25-217</cite> amended <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-333" path="§9">section 9 of D.C. Law 24-333</cite> making the creation of this section by section 5(d)(2) of D.C. Law 24-333 applicable as of October 1, 2025.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-09-18" doc="D.C. Law 25-217" eff="2024-09-18" path="§7286" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
