<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1646</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Disqualification from appointment as receiver; disclosure of interest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may not appoint a person as receiver unless the person submits to the Superior Court a statement under penalty of perjury that the person is not disqualified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person is disqualified from appointment as receiver if the person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is an affiliate of a party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has an interest materially adverse to an interest of a party;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has a material financial interest in the outcome of the action, other than compensation the Superior Court may allow the receiver;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Has a debtor-creditor relationship with a party; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Holds an equity interest in a party, other than a noncontrolling interest in a publicly-traded company.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person is not disqualified from appointment as receiver solely because the person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Was appointed receiver or is owed compensation in an unrelated matter involving a party or was engaged by a party in a matter unrelated to the receivership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is an individual obligated to a party on a debt that is not in default and was incurred primarily for personal, family, or household purposes; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintains with a party a deposit account, as that term is defined in <cite path="ยง28:9-102|(a)|(29)">ยง 28:9-102(a)(29)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person seeking appointment of a receiver may nominate a person to serve as receiver, but the Superior Court is not bound by the nomination.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง8" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
