<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1652</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Duties of owner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An owner shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assist and cooperate with the receiver in the administration of the receivership and the discharge of the receiver's duties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Preserve and turn over to the receiver all receivership property in the owner's possession, custody, or control;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identify all records and other information relating to the receivership property, including a password, authorization, or other information needed to obtain or maintain access to or control of the receivership property, and make available to the receiver the records and information in the owner's possession, custody, or control;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>On subpoena, submit to examination under oath by the receiver concerning the acts, conduct, property, liabilities, and financial condition of the owner or any matter relating to the receivership property or the receivership; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Perform any duty imposed by Superior Court order, <cite path="42|16B">this chapter</cite>, or law of the District other than this act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an owner is a person other than an individual, this section applies to each officer, director, manager, member, partner, trustee, or other person exercising or having the power to exercise control over the affairs of the owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a person knowingly fails to perform a duty imposed by this section, the Superior Court may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Award the receiver actual damages caused by the person's failure, reasonable attorney's fees, and costs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sanction the failure as civil contempt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง14" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
