<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1643</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Scope; exclusions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) or (c) of this section, <cite path="42|16B">this act</cite> applies to a receivership for an interest in real property and any personal property related to or used in operating the real property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text><cite path="42|16B">This act</cite> does not apply to a receivership for an interest in real property improved by one to 4 dwelling units unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The interest is used for agricultural, commercial, industrial, or mineral-extraction purposes, other than incidental uses by an owner occupying the property as the owner's primary residence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The interest secures an obligation incurred at a time when the property was used or planned for use for agricultural, commercial, industrial, or mineral-extraction purposes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The owner planned or is planning to develop the property into one or more dwelling units to be sold or leased in the ordinary course of the owner's business; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The owner is collecting or has the right to collect rents or other income from the property from a person other than an affiliate of the owner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text><cite path="42|16B">This act</cite> does not apply to a receivership authorized by law of the District other than this act in which the receiver is a governmental unit or an individual acting in an official capacity on behalf of the governmental unit except to the extent provided by the other law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text><cite path="42|16B">This act</cite> does not limit the authority of the Superior Court to appoint a receiver under law of the District other than this act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Unless displaced by a particular provision of <cite path="42|16B">this act</cite>, the principles of law and equity supplement this act.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง5" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
