<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-1653</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Stay; injunction.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section or ordered by the Superior Court, an order appointing a receiver operates as a stay, applicable to all persons, of an act, action, or proceeding:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To obtain possession of, exercise control over, or enforce a judgment against receivership property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To enforce a lien against receivership property to the extent the lien secures a claim against the owner which arose before entry of the order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Superior Court may enjoin an act, action, or proceeding against or relating to receivership property if the injunction is necessary to protect the property or facilitate administration of the receivership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person whose act, action, or proceeding is stayed or enjoined under this section may apply to the Superior Court for relief from the stay or injunction for cause.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An order under subsection (a) or (b) of this section does not operate as a stay or injunction of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An act, action, or proceeding to foreclose or otherwise enforce a mortgage by the person seeking appointment of the receiver;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An act, action, or proceeding to perfect, or maintain or continue the perfection of, an interest in receivership property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Commencement or continuation of a criminal proceeding;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Commencement or continuation of an action or proceeding, or enforcement of a judgment other than a money judgment in an action or proceeding, by a governmental unit to enforce its police or regulatory power; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Establishment by a governmental unit of a tax liability against the owner or receivership property or an appeal of the liability.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court may void an act that violates a stay or injunction under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If a person knowingly violates a stay or injunction under this section, the Superior Court may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Award actual damages caused by the violation, reasonable attorney's fees, and costs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sanction the violation as civil contempt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-269" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง15" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
