<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3502.15</num>
  <heading>Voluntary agreement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to rules and procedures enacted under <cite path="§42-3502.02|(a)|(1)">§ 42-3502.02(a)(1)</cite>, 70%, or more of the tenants of a housing accommodation may enter into a voluntary agreement with the housing provider:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To establish the reasonable rent charged;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To alter levels of related services and facilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To provide for capital improvements and the elimination of deferred maintenance (ordinary repair).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>A tenant in a unit exempt from the Rent Stabilization Program under <cite path="§42-3502.05|(a)">§ 42-3502.05(a)</cite> shall be permitted to comment on the provisions of a voluntary agreement and shall have their comments included in any filing of a voluntary agreement to the Rent Administrator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A housing provider, tenant, or tenant association shall file a voluntary agreement with the Rent Administrator. If approved by the Rent Administrator, the agreement shall be binding on the housing provider and on all tenants, except as specified in <cite path="§42-3502.24|(i)|(2)">§ 42-3502.24(i)(2)</cite>. The voluntary agreement shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The signature of each tenant, including that of a tenant who opted out of the voluntary agreement pursuant to subsection (a-1) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of each tenant's rental unit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The specific amount of increased rent each tenant will pay, if applicable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A statement that the agreement was entered into voluntarily without any form of coercion, as defined by subsection (e) of this section, on the part of the housing provider;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An explanation of why the housing provider did not pursue a rent adjustment pursuant to §§ <cite path="§42-3502.10">42-3502.10</cite>, <cite path="§42-3502.11">42-3502.11</cite>, <cite path="§42-3502.12">42-3502.12</cite>, and <cite path="§42-3502.14">42-3502.14</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Rent Administrator requires.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall determine whether a voluntary agreement complies with filing requirements, was agreed to without coercion, and whether any proposed rent adjustments within a voluntary agreement are reasonable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "coercion" includes the knowing circulation of inaccurate information, frequent visits or calls over the objection of that household, threat of retaliatory action, an act or threat not otherwise permitted by law which seeks to recover possession of a rental unit, increase rent, decrease services, increase the obligation of a tenant or cause undue or unavoidable inconvenience, harass or violate the privacy of the household, refusal to honor a lease provision, refusal to renew a lease or rental agreement, or other form of threat.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History" path="§215">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 215, 32 DCR 3089</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-145" type="History">Aug. 5, 2006, D.C. Law 16-145, § 2(a), 53 DCR 4889</annotation>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§42-3502.01">§ 42-3502.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Rent Control Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-470, July 31, 2006,  53 DCR 6772).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-145">D.C. Law 16-145</cite>, in par. (a)(1) and subsec. (c), substituted “rent charged” for “rent ceiling”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-2525.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§42-3502.08">§ 42-3502.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-239" eff="2017-04-07" path="§3|(e)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§201|(a)|(5)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
