<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3131.18</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Publication of vacant and blighted vacant building information by the Department of Buildings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of Buildings shall maintain, on a publicly available website, a database or list of vacant buildings. The database or list shall, at a minimum, contain the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The address of the building, including the square, suffix, and lot number of the property on which the building is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Neighborhood Commission and Ward in which the building is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date on which the building was designated a vacant building or blighted vacant building or registered as a vacant building pursuant to <cite path="§42-3131.06">§ 42-3131.06</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The type of exemption the building has received, the date on which the building received an exemption, and the number of half tax years the building has been exempt, if applicable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of months the building has been registered or designated as vacant or designated as blighted vacant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The last date on which the property was inspected by the Department; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The current tax classification of the property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="§18">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, § 18</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-02-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-200" eff="2017-02-18" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-05" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" eff="2021-04-05" path="§501|(x)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-41" eff="2025-10-01" path="§202|(n)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
