<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3131.05b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Determination of vacancy and blight.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When making a determination that a building is vacant, the Mayor shall consider the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Neighbor complaints;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commission certification;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Accumulated mail, fliers, or newspapers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Past due utility notices, disconnected utilities, or low utility usage inconsistent with regular and habitual occupancy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Presence of overgrown vegetation, dead or diseased trees, or noxious weeds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Absence of furnishings or personal items consistent with habitation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Building is open to casual entry or trespass; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any other criteria the Mayor deems relevant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When making a determination that a vacant building is a blighted vacant building, the Mayor shall consider the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Incidence of illegal activity, as documented by police reports;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether the vacant building is the subject of a condemnation proceeding before the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Referrals to the Department of Buildings from other District agencies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>One or more windows, doors, or other means of entry are missing or boarded up;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Collapsing, missing, or deteriorating walls, roof, stairs, porches, balconies, chimneys, and other building elements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Siding or exterior walls that are seriously damaged, missing, or deteriorating;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Trash and debris are improperly stored or accumulated on the premises;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Building shows visible signs of vandalism, such as graffiti;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Presence of mold, algae, abandoned or wild animals, or insect or pest infestation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any other criteria the Mayor deems relevant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch1626" path="ยง5b">Apr. 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 115, ch. 1626, ยง 5b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-10-01" doc="D.C. Law 26-41" eff="2025-10-01" path="ยง202|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
