<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1005.07</num>
  <heading>Special meeting of members.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A special meeting of members shall be called only:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As provided in the organic rules;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a majority vote of the board of directors on a proposal stating the purpose of the meeting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By demand in a record signed by members holding at least 20% of the voting power of the persons in any district or class entitled to vote on the matter that is the purpose of the meeting stated in the demand; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By demand in a record signed by members holding at least 10% of the total voting power of all the persons entitled to vote on the matter that is the purpose of the meeting stated in the demand.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A demand under subsection (a)(3) or (4) of this section shall be submitted to the officer of the limited cooperative association charged with keeping its records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any voting member may withdraw its demand under subsection (a)(3) or (4) of this section before receipt by the limited cooperative association of demands sufficient to require a special meeting of members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A special meeting of members may be held inside or outside the District at the place stated in the organic rules or selected by the board of directors not inconsistent with the organic rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Members may attend or conduct a special meeting of members through the use of any means of communication if all members attending the meeting can communicate with each other during the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Only business within the purpose or purposes stated in the notice of a special meeting of members shall be conducted at the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, the presiding officer of a special meeting of members shall be designated by the board of directors.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 507 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1001.09">§ 29-1001.09</cite> and <cite path="§29-1005.08">§ 29-1005.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-6" path="§3|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-02-13" eff="2025-02-13">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-6" path="§3|(c)">§ 3(c) of Association Meeting Flexibility Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-6, Feb. 13, 2025, 72 DCR 1643)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-02-13" doc="D.C. Act 26-6" eff="2025-02-13" path="§3|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-53" path="§3|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-04-22" eff="2025-04-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-53" path="§3|(c)">§ 3(c) of Association Meeting Flexibility Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-53, Apr. 22, 2025, 72 DCR 4909)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-04-22" doc="D.C. Act 26-53" eff="2025-04-22" path="§3|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-05-02" doc="D.C. Law 25-324" eff="2025-05-02" path="§304" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 26-2" path="§3|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2025-05-03" eff="2025-05-03">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 26-2" path="§3|(c)">§ 3(c) of Association Meeting Flexibility Temporary Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Law 26-2, May 3, 2025, 72 DCR 3107)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 26-2" eff="2025-05-03" path="§3|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
