<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-102.13</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on February 22, 2026. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§29-102.13(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Establishment of Corporate Recordation Fund; disposition of entity filing fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Corporate Recordation Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection in accordance with subsection (b) of this section. The Fund shall be credited with all fees:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That are identified in <cite path="§29-102.12">§ 29-102.12</cite> that are collected for Chapters 10, 12, and 13;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That are identified as expedited fees and the fees collected for the enforcement of Chapters 10, 12, and 13; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Collected for the processing of corporate filings, including renewals, fines, and option service fees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revenue credited to the Fund shall be expended by the Department of Licensing and Consumer Protection for the purposes of maintaining and upgrading the corporate filing system, including copying fees, automation upgrades, personnel costs, and supplies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Any money remaining available in the Fund at the end of a fiscal year, as determined by the Chief Financial Officer in the fiscal year-end close, shall be transferred to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia as part of the fiscal year-end close.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Fees and charges payable to the Mayor shall be paid at the time of presenting a document for filing or making a request for information for which a fee or charge is payable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Overpayments and duplicate and erroneous payments shall be refunded. A mere change of purpose after the payment of money, as when a party desires to withdraw a filing, shall not entitle a party to a refund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except noted under subsection (d) of this section, all other fees shall be deemed processing fees and shall be nonrefundable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may cancel a processed filing due to nonpayment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-305" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-305, § 2(c), 60 DCR 2735</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-305">D.C. Law 19-305</cite> substituted “10, 12, and 13” for “10 and 12” in (a)(1) and (a)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-2855.05">§ 47-2855.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-05" doc="D.C. Law 23-269" eff="2021-04-05" path="§501|(o)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7084" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-03" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§7084">§ 7084 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§7084" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7084" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7084|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7084|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-11-24" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§7084|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7084" codified:display="Note" app="2025-11-24" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§7084">§ 7084 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
